<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Canberra Liberals</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news</link><description>The lastest News, Media Releases and Speeches from the Canberra Liberals</description><language>en-AU</language><copyright>Copyright Canberra Liberals</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 13:00:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Scrapy 2.4.1</generator><item><title>Transport Minister continues to keep Canberrans in the dark on tram</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/01/transport-minister-continues-keep-canberrans-dark-tram</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144019" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/11/01/transport-minister-continues-keep-canberrans-dark-tram" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Transport Minister continues to keep Canberrans in the dark on tram" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transport Minister Chris Steel has once again refused to provide a
completion date for Light Rail stage 2A, despite federal infrastructure
officials telling Senate Estimates last Friday works would commence in January
2024 and be completed by January 2026.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A number of questions were also put to the Minister in Annual
Reports Hearings yesterday afternoon regarding funding following revelations
that three Canberra road projects funded by the federal government were axed to
pay for the tram.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Canberra Liberals Leader and Shadow Minister for Major Projects
Elizabeth Lee said the information out of Senate Hearings last week begs the
question what else is on the chopping block?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We already know the ACT Labor-Greens government has taken
hundreds of millions of taxpayer dollars from health and public housing to pay
for the tram,” Ms Lee said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In hearings yesterday, the Minister said all ACT road projects
were considered for the chopping block in order to divert funds to the
tram.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Canberrans have every right to feel betrayed by Labor and the
Greens’ decision to rip $85.9 million out of these very important road
upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There are a number of inconsistencies between the information the
federal government is providing in regard to the tram and what the Minister is
telling Canberrans and he must be upfront.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Minister also failed to adequately answer questions from
Shadow Transport Minister Mark Parton regarding the cost and timeframe for
stage 2 of the light rail.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It is firstly astounding that federal government officials are
able and willing to confirm the timeframe for the completion of stage 2A and
yet the responsible ACT Minister cannot and will not be upfront with the public,”
Mr Parton said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It is also telling that the Minister would not correct the
assertion that stage 2 in it’s entirety will cost over $3 billion and not
arrive in Woden until at least 2034.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This entire project is shrouded in secrecy and by the Minister’s own
admission regardless of what the business case says, the Labor-Greens
government will push ahead with the tram to Woden, even if it does not
represent value for money,” Mr Parton concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Elizabeth Lee &amp; Mark Parton</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/01/transport-minister-continues-keep-canberrans-dark-tram</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 10:22:09 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Elizabeth Lee calls for independent inquiry into poverty in the ACT</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/13/elizabeth-lee-calls-independent-inquiry-poverty-act</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144006" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/10/13/elizabeth-lee-calls-independent-inquiry-poverty-act" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Elizabeth Lee calls for independent inquiry into poverty in the ACT" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Canberra Liberals Leader Elizabeth Lee has highlighted the concerning number of Canberrans living in poverty and called on the Labor-Greens government to commission an independent inquiry into the prevalence of poverty in the ACT.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Ms Lee who will put forward a motion in the Legislative Assembly today, said the ACT Council of Social Services (ACTCOSS) estimates that a staggering 38,000 Canberrans are living in poverty including 9000 children.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“The recent cost of living increases has hit lower income Canberrans the hardest and for ACT to have 38,000 people living in poverty is simply unacceptable,” Ms Lee said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Early last year, I put forward a motion in the Legislative Assembly calling for a Poverty Taskforce to investigate the ongoing causes of poverty in the ACT.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“This motion was ultimately voted down by every member of Labor and the Greens who said it was not warranted because they already understood the root causes of poverty in the ACT and were implementing the necessary measures to address the problem.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Since that time, more than two thirds of community sector staff in the ACT have reported that levels of poverty and disadvantage amongst vulnerable groups have increased over the last year.”&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In its submission to the ACT Budget 2022-23 ACTCOSS also reported.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;the ACT has the highest rate of rental stress among      lower income households in private rentals&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;over 25,000 Canberrans living in low-income households&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;households in the lowest income quintile spend over 55      percent of their income on housing, food and transport.&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Despite the lip service offered to Canberrans, clearly the Labor-Greens government is either unable or unwilling to address the issue of poverty in the ACT,” Ms Lee said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“This government continues to have the hubris to act as if they have not been responsible for years of neglect in the Housing and Community Services sectors.”&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The independent inquiry into the prevalence of poverty in Canberra would look at a number of factors including the rates and drivers of poverty; the relationships between economic conditions and poverty and the impact of poverty on individuals in relation to employment, housing, health and education.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The inquiry would also examine the effects of poverty in different demographics and communities; the relationship between income support payments and poverty and mechanisms to address and reduce poverty.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Elizabeth Lee</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/13/elizabeth-lee-calls-independent-inquiry-poverty-act</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 09:35:24 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Parton lashes Labor-Greens plan to end racing in the ACT</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/02/parton-lashes-labor-greens-plan-end-racing-act</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144021" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/11/02/parton-lashes-labor-greens-plan-end-racing-act" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Parton lashes Labor-Greens plan to end racing in the ACT" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shadow Minister for Gaming and Racing Mark Parton has lashed out at the Labor-Greens government following the release of a development plan to absorb Thoroughbred Park that would see racing scrapped in the ACT.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Mr Parton said the proposal was put forward under the draft Inner North and City District Strategy Proposal as part of the Territory Plan released yesterday without any consultation whatsoever with the race club.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“This is an utter disgrace and what we see here is clear proof that the ACT is genuinely staring down the barrel of being the only jurisdiction in Australia without horse racing,” Mr Parton said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Canberrans should be very concerned with how two faced this Labor-Greens government is. This is not how consultation works and to release a very clear plan to end racing in the ACT on Melbourne Cup day is cruel.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Labor and the Greens have now put forward their intention to stop racing in the ACT to develop the land at Thoroughbred Park to help pay for the tram.&lt;/p&gt;  “The race club has been completely blindsided by this when they are busy putting on a Melbourne Cup raceday and once again the ACT Greens are dictating terms to the Labor Party on this matter,” Mr Parton concluded.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Mark Parton</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/02/parton-lashes-labor-greens-plan-end-racing-act</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Minister limits community’s opportunity to provide feedback on the future of planning</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/01/minister-limits-communitys-opportunity-provide-feedback-future-planning</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144020" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/11/01/minister-limits-communitys-opportunity-provide-feedback-future-planning" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content=" Minister limits community’s opportunity to provide feedback on the future of planning" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Labor-Greens Government yesterday confirmed in Annual Reports Hearings that Canberrans will be receiving the new District Strategies and Territory Plan this week, well after the planning Bill introduced to the Assembly.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Shadow Minister for Planning Peter Cain said the Canberra Liberals have heard from community organisations and industry across Canberra that this release schedule has made it difficult to get the full picture of the future of Planning under this Labor-Greens Government.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Keeping the community and industry in the dark certainly makes the Labor-Greens Government’s job of introducing huge planning reform easier, as they don’t have to address as much informed feedback,” Mr Cain said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“The community has told us they can’t provide meaningful feedback on the future of planning, or even the planning Bill, without the District Strategies and Territory Plan. Clearly the Labor-Greens Government doesn’t want to hear community feedback or incorporate it.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;"This Labor-Greens Government does not trust Canberrans to provide meaningful feedback, and they have proven time and time again they don’t want to hear a lot of the feedback communities have, especially in regard to the future of planning in the ACT” Mr Cain concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Peter Cain</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/01/minister-limits-communitys-opportunity-provide-feedback-future-planning</guid><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 11:06:02 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Cain questions Fair Trading Commissioner’s alleged conflict of interest</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/08/cain-questions-fair-trading-commissioners-alleged-conflict-interest</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144025" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/11/08/cain-questions-fair-trading-commissioners-alleged-conflict-interest" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Cain questions Fair Trading Commissioner’s alleged conflict of interest" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A concerning potential conflict of interest was raised in Annual Reports hearings today regarding the involvement of the Fair-Trading Commissioner of the ACT, Derise Cubin in current legal proceedings against the office of the Commissioner for Fair Trading, on a matter involving her partner, David Snowden, the former Commissioner for Fair Trading.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In her capacity as Fair-Trading Commissioner, Ms Cubin is alleged to have attended a mediation meeting in July 2021 and provided instructions to the ACT Government Solicitor in a civil matter relating to the Office of Fair Trading and the conduct of Mr Snowden.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The Attorney-General responded apprehensively to Shadow Attorney-General Peter Cain’s line of questioning, acknowledging the seriousness of the situation and confirming he is seeking advice from the Office of Fair Trading and the ACT Government Solicitor’s Office.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Ms Cubin was also present at the hearing but when asked by Mr Cain if she provided any advice on the matter prior to declaring the conflict, she responded ‘no comment’.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“This is an incredibly serious situation and is another indictment on this Labor-Greens government’s persistent lack of competence, and integrity,” Mr Cain said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“The Attorney-General sat on his hands for months while Ms Cubin allegedly advised the ACT Government Solicitor on the conduct of the person at the centre of the claim, who is her partner and predecessor, only declaring her conflict in November 2021 when it became unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“The Attorney-General must consider taking strong action to demonstrate his commitment to integrity in government and accountability in the public sector.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“This situation is extremely concerning and Canberrans deserve better from their government,” Mr Cain concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Peter Cain</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/08/cain-questions-fair-trading-commissioners-alleged-conflict-interest</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 16:51:40 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Chief Minister avoids answering questions on MPC contracts</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/04/chief-minister-avoids-answering-questions-mpc-contracts</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144022" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/11/04/chief-minister-avoids-answering-questions-mpc-contracts" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Chief Minister avoids answering questions on MPC contracts" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In Annual Reports Hearings today the Chief Minister has sought to
avoid taking on notice providing details on Major Projects Canberra contracts
where the final contracted price exceeds the price in the winning tender.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shadow Assistant Treasurer Peter Cain asked Head of Major Projects
Canberra Duncan Edghill to take on notice all contracts above $500,000 where
the final price was materially above the tendered price.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Chief Minister interjected saying that there would be “tens of
thousands of contracts” and would be too much work to provide.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Cain said given the ACT contract register has only awarded 134
contracts of that value or higher across the history of Major Project Canberra,
what is the Chief Minister trying to hide?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The concern is companies can provide low-ball offers to win
tenders with the expectation they can secure a higher price later on," Mr
Cain said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Transparency in government is essential to community confidence
in democracy and the sound and prudent expenditure of their taxpayer dollars.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I call on Mr Barr and Major Projects Canberra to provide details
on all projects where the final contract price exceeds the price in the winning
tender. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I also call on the Chief Minister to disclose where the
scope of the tender changed during contract negotiations,” Mr Cain concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Peter Cain</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/04/chief-minister-avoids-answering-questions-mpc-contracts</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:42:12 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Labor-Greens government fails to maintain floating wetlands</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/08/labor-greens-government-fails-maintain-floating-wetlands</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144024" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/11/08/labor-greens-government-fails-maintain-floating-wetlands" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Labor-Greens government fails to maintain floating wetlands " class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shadow Minister for Water Nicole Lawder has been left dismayed after questions regarding the maintenance of water assets such as the floating wetlands in Lake Tuggeranong went unanswered in Annual Reports Hearings for the second day in a row.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Despite being told by the Minister for Water yesterday the floating wetlands were the responsibility of TCCS, the City Services Minister and his officials were unsure if they were responsible for the maintenance of these expensive assets when questioned today.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Ms Lawder said following recent rain, the floating wetlands have fallen apart and are spreading debris throughout Lake Tuggeranong.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“This is the second time I have raised with the government that the floating wetlands have been damaged and are scattering debris throughout Lake Tuggeranong,” Shadow Minister for Water Nicole Lawder said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“It makes you seriously question what sort of maintenance, if any, the Labor-Greens government is undertaking on our water quality assets.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“This government is spending millions of ratepayers’ dollars on installing these assets and they love to announce them with much fanfare and pats on the back for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Yet they are continuing to fail to maintain and inspect these assets to the point that they are deteriorating and just adding to the problem of poor water quality in the lake.  &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“The same issues continue to rise with the Labor-Greens government’s approach to improving water quality in our lakes and waterways. A failure to communicate between the responsible directorates and a failure to maintain and measure the impact of these assets.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“How many times do assets including the floating wetlands, that cost millions of dollars to install, have to be broken and reported to the government before they start proactively and adequately maintaining them?” Ms Lawder concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Nicole Lawder</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/08/labor-greens-government-fails-maintain-floating-wetlands</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 14:42:42 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Canberra Liberals vote against ACT Greens' attack on horse racing</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/13/canberra-liberals-vote-against-act-greens-attack-horse-racing</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144012" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/10/13/canberra-liberals-vote-against-act-greens-attack-horse-racing" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Canberra Liberals vote against ACT Greens' attack on horse racing" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Canberra Liberals have voted against the Greens’ ridiculous amendment to the ACT Budget to stop funding to the horse racing industry.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Shadow Minister for Gaming and Racing Mark Parton said the Canberra Liberals stand alongside all those in the racing community and steadfastly support this line of spending in the budget.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“The Greens ideological war on this line of spending completely ignores any of the historical context of the funding,” Mr Parton said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“It completely ignores the fact that when the government sold ACTTAB to Tabcorp that there was a steadfast promise to the racing codes to continue with a similar level of funding in the years ahead.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“At a time when this government’s coffers are being bolstered enormously by the point of consumption gaming tax, a tax which has just been severely increased by this government, it’s ludicrous to suggest that some of that money should not be distributed back to the racing codes.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“The Greens have a vision of how all of us should live, they have a vision of the pastimes that we should enjoy and of the way that we should go about our lives. They wish to stop the rest of us doing the things that give us joy, if those things don’t align with their values.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“The vast majority of those involved in the racing industry in this town are minimum wage battlers. They’re salt of the earth people who often are working a number of jobs to try to pay the rent and put food on the table.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“These are the people who would be most hurt by this line of spending being struck out of the budget,” Mr Parton concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Mark Parton</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/13/canberra-liberals-vote-against-act-greens-attack-horse-racing</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Canberra Liberals welcome FuelCheck announcement after years of inaction from Labor and the Greens</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/04/canberra-liberals-welcome-fuelcheck-announcement-after-years-inaction-labor-and</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144023" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/11/04/canberra-liberals-welcome-fuelcheck-announcement-after-years-inaction-labor-and" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Canberra Liberals welcome FuelCheck announcement after years of inaction from Labor and the Greens" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shadow
Minister for Regulatory Services, Ed Cocks MLA has today welcomed the ACT Labor-Greens
Government adoption of the Canberra Liberals policy and the announcement that
the ACT will finally have access to a Government FuelCheck app. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The
Labor-Green Government had previously cast doubt on the policy suggesting it
would be only marginally effective, signalling that the Government may ignore
the recommendation which was made by the Select Committee on Fuel Pricing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr
Cocks said despite the ACT Labor-Greens Government’s hesitancy to enact
important cost of living initiatives, he was glad they had finally come to
the table after the New South Wales Liberal Government waived the cost. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The
Canberra Liberals welcome the introduction of the FuelCheck system into the
ACT, but questions remain about the difference between the ACT's approach
and that used in NSW.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It's
critical that FuelCheck is set up to succeed and given this is a 6-month
pilot program we will be interested to see how the Government evaluates it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We
thank the NSW Government for assisting the ACT in this way and the use of their
system,” Mr Cocks concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Ed Cocks</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/11/04/canberra-liberals-welcome-fuelcheck-announcement-after-years-inaction-labor-and</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2022 14:42:58 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Lee to introduce bill to allow telephone interception powers for integrity commission</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/17/lee-introduce-bill-allow-telephone-interception-powers-integrity-commission</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144011" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/10/17/lee-introduce-bill-allow-telephone-interception-powers-integrity-commission" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Lee to introduce bill to allow telephone interception powers for integrity commission" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Canberra Liberals Leader Elizabeth Lee will present a bill in the Legislative Assembly this week that would allow the ACT Integrity Commission to have telecommunication interception powers.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The Integrity Commissioner has discussed in Annual Reports for the last two years and Estimates Hearings the urgent need to have telecommunications interception powers in order to conduct investigations properly.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The Commissioner also went on to say in hearings last month that the AFP has indicated they have material that would be of assistance to investigations but due to current legislation he is unable to access it.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Ms Lee said the ACT along with Tasmania are the only jurisdictions whose integrity body does not have the legal authority to intercept telecommunications.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Integrity in government is of utmost importance and it is disappointing the ACT remains one of the only jurisdictions where the integrity body does not have this power,” Ms Lee said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“In the recent Estimates Hearings, the Integrity Commissioner revealed the Chief Minister has not even responded to his request for a meeting regarding critical changes required in legislation, specifically telephone interception powers.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“The Chief Minister continues to delay implementing this important piece of legislation and is clearly dragging his heels on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“We know this Labor-Greens government has no interest in transparency, but the Integrity Commission must be given the resources it needs to conduct thorough investigations.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“We have seen just this year significant integrity issues around the Campbell Primary Modernisation Project, the CIT contracts and Acton Waterfront project and the Commission must be given the resources to investigate these matters,” Ms Lee concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Elizabeth Lee</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/17/lee-introduce-bill-allow-telephone-interception-powers-integrity-commission</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Canberra Liberals call for the acceleration of the Age Friendly City Plan</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/18/canberra-liberals-call-acceleration-age-friendly-city-plan</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144010" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/10/18/canberra-liberals-call-acceleration-age-friendly-city-plan" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Canberra Liberals call for the acceleration of the Age Friendly City Plan " class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shadow Minister for Seniors Nicole Lawder will today move a motion calling on the ACT Labor- Greens Government to accelerate the footpath maintenance component of the Age Friendly City Plan and the initiatives to support Canberra becoming a Dementia-Friendly City.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The motion also calls on the ACT Government to write to the Federal Government in support of a UN Convention on the Rights of Older Persons.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Older Canberrans are understandably concerned about the dire state of footpaths in the ACT.  They are more vulnerable to falls and rely on footpaths for exercise and mobility,” Ms Lawder said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“It’s the basic maintenance components of the Age Friendly City Plan that matter most to older Canberrans which is why I’m calling on the government to accelerate this work.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;"Ensuring that our city is accessible to all should be of the highest priority to this government.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Similarly, by accelerating the work on making Canberra a Dementia-Friendly City we can help improve our city for people living with dementia and their carers.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“It is staggering that the Minister is unable to provide a straight answer as to whether frontline staff such as bus drivers have been given dementia-friendly training.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“These are simple, low-cost initiatives that can make the world of difference to older Canberrans and prevent future accidents. Many seniors feel ignored by this Labor Greens Government and by moving things along faster we can help improve the quality of life for older people in our community.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Older people advocacy organisations have long been calling for the introduction of a UN Convention of the Rights of Older Persons. I see no reason why the ACT Government can’t write to the Federal Government about this matter,” Ms Lawder concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Nicole Lawder</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/18/canberra-liberals-call-acceleration-age-friendly-city-plan</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 10:05:53 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Labor’s backflip on wiping ACT housing debt must be called out</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/19/labors-backflip-wiping-act-housing-debt-must-be-called-out</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144013" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/10/19/labors-backflip-wiping-act-housing-debt-must-be-called-out" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Labor’s backflip on wiping ACT housing debt must be called out" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shadow Minister for Housing Mark Parton will put forward a motion in the Legislative Assembly today calling on the leaders of all parties represented to write to the Federal Finance Minister Katy Gallagher condemning her backflip on her pre-election promise and to waive the historic ACT housing debt.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Senator Katy Gallagher campaigned to waive the ACT Government’s $98.3 million public housing debt during the 2022 federal election campaign however just last week, the now Finance Minister said ‘the federal government is not in a position to waive the territory’s historic housing debt'.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In opposition, Senator Gallagher was critical of the Federal Coalition government for not having waived the ACT’s historic housing debt. In 2019 senate Estimates on October 22, Senator Gallagher said to Senator Seselja as Assistant Minister for Finance, in respect to waiving the debt, ‘You’re in a position of power. You get to sign it off.’&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In 2019, Chief Minister Andrew Barr also stated, ‘I would observe that it is an odd state of affairs when a crossbench senator from Tasmania can achieve more through Liberal Government than an ACT Liberal senator who is a member of the government executive as an assistant minister, Senator Seselja’.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Mr Parton said by not waiving this debt, it shows that public housing is not a priority for Federal Labor and it is not a priority for the ACT Labor-Greens government.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“If the Chief Minister and his Greens colleagues are serious about public housing in the ACT, they will agree to this motion, condemn Senator Gallagher in the strongest terms on her backflip and call for the debt to be wiped,” Mr Parton said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Despite the Chief Minister’s rhetoric since the federal election, it appears the ACT government has no sway with the federal government if they are unable to have this debt waived as was indicated prior to the election.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“In August 2022, the current Federal Labor Government said to the ACT Government to ask for more light rail funding when you’re ready, as part of a media announcement on the tram, yet the ACT was snubbed from any infrastructure funding in the recent Federal announcement.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“ACT Labor are happy to spend big on the tram because that is their priority, not public housing and not paying off their debt.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Once again, this ACT Government has failed to deliver for Canberrans. You can’t trust Labor’s promises and you can’t trust Labor when it comes to public housing,” Mr Parton concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Mark Parton</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/19/labors-backflip-wiping-act-housing-debt-must-be-called-out</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 08:21:47 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Labor-Greens government must be open and transparent on land release</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/19/labor-greens-government-must-be-open-and-transparent-land-release</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144014" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/10/19/labor-greens-government-must-be-open-and-transparent-land-release" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Labor-Greens government must be open and transparent on land release" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Canberra Liberals Leader and Shadow Minister for Housing Affordability and Choice Elizabeth Lee will move a motion in the Legislative Assembly today, calling on the ACT Labor-Greens government to be more open and transparent when it comes to the indicative land release program (ILRP).&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Last week, the Standing Committee on Public Accounts made a series of recommendations to address the ACT’s housing crisis in the report on its inquiry into &lt;em&gt;Auditor-General’s Report No 4 of 2020: Residential Supply and Release.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Ms Lee said the Canberra Liberals have continually raised a number of concerns when it comes to land release in the ACT, but the Labor-Greens government is wedded to a high-rise apartment policy that is not meeting the wider needs of the community.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;"Labor and the Greens must accept the considerable impact their polices are having on the housing affordability crisis and the serious effect it is having on our community,” Ms Lee said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“The ACT continues to have the highest median rents in the country and recent ballots for detached housing have attracted tens of thousands of applicants for a mere couple hundred blocks of land.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“This motion is calling on the Labor-Greens government to establish an inventory of serviced land and to ensure future ILRPs include a clear set of classification for block types and reporting requirements against delivery of those each financial year.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“We know that year on year the Labor-Greens government is failing to meet already low land release targets and they must be upfront with Canberrans when it comes to the details of how they are releasing land to the public.&lt;/p&gt;  “It is also imperative that the ACT government publish for public scrutiny and analysis, its residential supply and demand model along with the policy guidance and criteria for the identification and allocation of affordable housing in the ILRP,” Ms Lee concluded.&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Elizabeth Lee</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/19/labor-greens-government-must-be-open-and-transparent-land-release</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 08:22:27 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Canberra Liberals thank ACT Police</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/20/canberra-liberals-thank-act-police</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144016" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/10/20/canberra-liberals-thank-act-police" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Canberra Liberals thank ACT Police" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jeremy Hanson, Shadow Minister for Police, will move a motion in the Assembly this afternoon to recognise and thank police in the ACT.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“For some years, the ACT’s thin blue line has been stretched very thin indeed,” said Mr Hanson.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“First there were the bushfires. Then we rolled straight into an unprecedented pandemic, including the protests, with police on the front line. We heard reports of officers turning up to work and then sleeping in their cars for fear of brining COVID home to their families.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“That is on top of the situation of recent deliberate attacks on police as they try to deal with repeat offenders and drug affected drivers.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“This is not about politics. Previously, motions like this have received tri-partisan support.  This is about recognising the very real dangers and difficulties police face day after day, year after year.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“It is also timely, as the National Police Memorial Day has just passed, where officers from around the country paid respects for those who paid the ultimate price in keeping our community safe. As AFP Commissioner Kershaw said:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Policing is a service and an honour. For those of us who heed this call, we are aware of our heavy responsibility, and the perils that come with it. We choose this vocation not for ourselves, but for our communities and for our country.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I couldn’t agree more. I hope everyone in the Assembly feels the same and will join me in commending our police for the job they do for the entire ACT community,” concluded Mr Hanson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Jeremy Hanson</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/20/canberra-liberals-thank-act-police</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 14:09:44 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Report highlights concerning problems with paediatric care in the ACT</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/21/report-highlights-concerning-problems-paediatric-care-act</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144017" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/10/21/report-highlights-concerning-problems-paediatric-care-act" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Report highlights concerning problems with paediatric care in the ACT" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A damning report into paediatric services in the ACT has been tabled in the Legislative Assembly.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The report, which the Minister attempted to sneak through the Assembly yesterday with a nothing to see here approach contains scathing feedback from stakeholders which has resulted in an extensive list of priority issues in the paediatric division.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Shadow Minister for Health Leanne Castley said the Canberra Liberals have continually called out inadequate paediatric care in the ACT as have nurses, paediatricians and families.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“This Labor-Greens government has dropped the ball and our children have borne the brunt,” Ms Castley said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Despite the Minister continually stating everything is working as it should, this report clearly shows paediatric care in the ACT is not up to scratch and doesn’t even come close to what our children deserve.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“We knew it and we have called it out a number of times as have many families and it is a disgrace that this government has only responded when they were shamed into taking action.”&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The executive summary includes a list of 11 priority issues and actions which range from known workforce gaps, limited formal arrangements with the Sydney Children’s Hospital Network and to improve the management of critically ill and deteriorating children.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“The action items put forward must be kicked off immediately as it highlights significant gaps in caring for Canberra’s sick children,” Ms Castley said.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“I have brought two motions to the Assembly in recent times calling on the ACT government to improve paediatric care and on both occasions all members of Labor and the Greens voted against improving care for sick children.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“Approximately one in five presentations to Canberra Hospital are children from the ACT and Southern NSW.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;“This report raises serious questions about the Health Minister's dismissive attitude regarding the state of paediatric services in the ACT,” Ms Castley concluded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Leanne Castley</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/21/report-highlights-concerning-problems-paediatric-care-act</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Oct 2022 08:07:32 +1100</pubDate></item><item><title>Canberra Liberals call for Barr to seek mandate or stop radical Heroin and Meth Bill</title><link>https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/20/canberra-liberals-call-barr-seek-mandate-or-stop-radical-heroin-and-meth-bill</link><description>&lt;div class="content"&gt;
        &lt;article id="node-144015" class="node node-article clearfix" about="/news/2022/10/20/canberra-liberals-call-barr-seek-mandate-or-stop-radical-heroin-and-meth-bill" typeof="sioc:Item foaf:Document"&gt;

  
      &lt;span property="dc:title" content="Canberra Liberals call for Barr to seek mandate or stop radical Heroin and Meth Bill" class="rdf-meta element-hidden"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;div class="content"&gt;
    &lt;div class="field field-name-body field-type-text-with-summary field-label-hidden"&gt;&lt;div class="field-items"&gt;&lt;div class="field-item even" property="content:encoded"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The
Canberra Liberals have lashed out at the under-handed move by Labor and the
Greens to force through radical changes to drug laws without a mandate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I
disagree strongly with these laws, but I’m absolutely appalled at the process
Labor and the Greens have gone through to pass them,” said Shadow Police
Minister and Deputy Leader Jeremy Hanson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“At
the last election, Labor did not mention changing laws for heroin, meth or
cocaine. Not before the election, and not during it. Not one word.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Yet
in the first year, a Labor member brought forward a bill to decriminalise
everything, including shocking drugs like heroin and meth. The Greens tried to
push it further, increasing the limit to allow months of supply to be
decriminalised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The
harm these drugs do is obvious and devastating. This approach has been tried
around the world, and has led to wreckage and misery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Yet
despite repeated calls to stop this dangerous reform from local
Commonwealth police, they are determined to push through without a mandate.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“That’s
why today I will move to delay the start of this Bill. It is already
slated to begin in 2023, I am calling for it to start in 2024, when the people
of Canberra can have their say, knowing exactly what the real plan is.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If
they are going to pursue these radical changes, it needs to be done with the
knowledge and agreement of your community, not snuck through with such contempt
for the community, the police, and the harms these drugs cause,” concluded Mr
Hanson.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Jeremy Hanson</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://canberraliberals.org.au/news/2022/10/20/canberra-liberals-call-barr-seek-mandate-or-stop-radical-heroin-and-meth-bill</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 09:52:01 +1100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>