<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Government of Queensland</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/</link><description>Media statements from the Queensland State Government</description><language>en-AU</language><copyright>Copyright State Government of Queensland</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 13:00:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Scrapy 2.4.1</generator><item><title>Premier’s Anzac Prize Winners</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96535</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="_Hlk114817660"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Eight Queensland students and two teacher chaperones have won the educational trip of a lifetime, awarded the Premier’s 2023 Anzac Prize.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk said she was delighted to announce the winners will visit some of Australia’s most important and historical war sites in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This year’s announcement is special,” the Premier said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It will be the first group to travel overseas since the Covid-19 pandemic began is 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s wonderful to see the travel component return and for our students to visit sites in London, Prance, and Belgium.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It will allow the group to see and hear first-hand, the Anzac tradition and become Ambassadors for the Anzac legacy when they return.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Previous winners have come home with a deep understanding and appreciation of the Anzac history and spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I’m also delighted to announce they’ll be accompanied by my Assistant Minister for Veterans, Bart Mellish, a tireless advocate for the RSL and our vets."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Education Minister Grace Grace said the winners were chosen from 40 high-quality applicants.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The students will be in years 9 to 12 when they travel in April,” Ms Grace said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This really is a life-changing experience.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s an opportunity to deepen their knowledge and appreciation of our Anzac history, and to experience the world, and share those experiences with their friends and fellow students.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One hundred and twenty-eight students have been awarded the prize since it began in 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The students will also take part in community engagement and fundraising projects before their trip.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2023 Premier’s Anzac Prize is presented in partnership with RSL Queensland, a platinum sponsor for the next three years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The 2023 winners are:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anastasia Maher (Emerald State High)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Claire Gattera (St Monica’s College Cairns)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dashiell Solomon (Ambrose Treacy College Indooroopilly)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hilman Pranowo (Pimlico State High)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nooria Ahmadi (Forest Lake High)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sarah Ellis ( St Joseph’s College Toowoomba)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thomas Eccleston (Ambrose Treacy)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tom Filipich (Pimlico State High)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The winning teacher chaperones are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alison Marsh (Marsden State High)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alexandra Cashin (Saint Mary’s Catholic College Kingaroy)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: underline;"&gt;Media Contact&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lane Calcutt (Premier's office) - 0411535191&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bryce Heaton (Minister Grace's office) - 0434575237&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Annastacia Palaszczuk &amp; The Honourable Grace Grace &amp; Mr Bart Mellish</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96535</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 23:56:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Flood Recovery Upskilling Queenslanders</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96531</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Up to 510 immediate job opportunities for displaced workers and local job seekers in disaster-affected South-East Queensland have been created, through the Commonwealth and Queensland governments’ $721 million flood recovery package.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twenty-six projects have now been approved under the $14.5 million &lt;em&gt;Small Business Recovery and Resilience&lt;/em&gt; package, which is jointly funded through the jointly funded Disaster Recovery Funding Arrangements (DRFA).&lt;a name="_Hlk115170362"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A total of 18 community-based organisations in the hardest hit areas have been approved to deliver Work Skills Traineeships that will support the recovery effort.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Federal Minister for Emergency Management Senator the Hon Murray Watt said the funding would lead to the creation of traineeships to assist with the clean-up, rebuilding and recovery efforts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Significant floods like the multiple events Queensland experienced earlier this year take time to recover from, but this is now another way we can build back better,” Minister Watt said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This is a fantastic initiative that will see construction, conservation and ecosystem traineeships used to deliver recovery works including fixing fences, restoring community building or recreation areas, refurbishing parks or sporting grounds and facilities or repairing walkways, bikeways and footpaths.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In the short-term, these projects help those trainees with their own community recovery and in the longer-term the trainees develop skills they can use into the future.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Queensland Minister for Training and Skills Development Di Farmer said the projects would provide Work Skills Traineeships including paid employment opportunities for up to six months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Queensland Government’s well-established Skilling Queenslanders for Work program has assisted more than 72,000 Queenslanders with skills development, training and job opportunities,” Minister Farmer said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We thank the Albanese Government for jointly funding these additional traineeships which will leave a visible and lasting impact on social and public infrastructure in local communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s not just construction and conservation traineeships that are being funded there are also business, hospitality and retail roles to support social enterprise cafes and other community activities in flood affected communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Traineeships are being offered in everything from repairing the Rocklea Showgrounds to rehabilitation works in bushland areas in Ipswich, to working in the RSPCA Black Cat café in Wacol.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This funding will also support local small businesses by providing a pool of skilled and job ready Queenslanders to meet employment needs.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alongside the $10 million &lt;em&gt;Skilling Queenslanders for Work&lt;/em&gt; program, the package will also provide:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under this Service, three additional Chamber of Commerce and Industry Queensland coordinators will also work with local Chambers to provide personalised and professional business information and will work directly with government agencies to assist in small business recovery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information on the Work Skills Traineeships projects approved through the Skilling Queenslanders for Work recovery package, go to:&lt;a href="https://desbt.qld.gov.au/training/community-orgs/funded/sqw/communityrecovery"&gt;https://desbt.qld.gov.au/training/community-orgs/funded/sqw/communityrecovery&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Watt: Brock Taylor 0499 779 387&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Farmer: John Jarrett 0460 284 096&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Di Farmer</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96531</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Better transport connection to Caloundra CBD a step closer</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96536</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Caloundra is another step closer to a new transport connection into its CBD, with a consultant appointed to finish the detailed design and a new group of community representatives coming together to provide feedback on the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aurecon has been announced as the detailed design consultant for Stage 2 of the Caloundra Transport Corridor Upgrade, connecting the CBD and Omrah Avenue to Nicklin Way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The extension is being delivered between Third Avenue from Arthur Street to Nicklin Way, with a connection to Industrial Avenue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; It will create a new access into the Caloundra CBD, reducing delays and congestion at the Caloundra Road/Nicklin Way roundabout.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of the design process, 10 community members have been selected to take part in a stakeholder interest group, which will provide important feedback that will be considered during a multi-criteria assessment of options.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Stakeholder Interest Group will provide important community feedback, which will be considered as part of a multi-criteria assessment of options along with traffic, flood and stormwater modelling, environmental and cultural heritage investigations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group’s first meeting will take place next month (December).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The members were selected to reflect a range of ages, demographics and interest areas representing residents, motorists, transport operators, businesses and local facilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the project progresses, the broader community will be kept informed of updated designs via regular updates and information available on the webpage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The $18.2 million project is jointly funded by the Australian Government, Queensland Government and Sunshine Coast Council.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is being delivered by Transport and Main Roads (TMR) and Sunshine Coast Council (SCC).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detailed design is expected to be completed in late 2023, with construction to follow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The project is due to be complete in late 2025, weather and construction conditions permitting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information and to register to receive updates, visit &lt;a href="http://www.tmr.qld.gov.au/projects/nicklin-way-third-avenue-extension-intersection"&gt;www.tmr.qld.gov.au/projects/nicklin-way-third-avenue-extension-intersection&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.sunshinecoast.qld.gov.au/CTCU"&gt;www.sunshinecoast.qld.gov.au/CTCU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes attributable to Queensland Transport and Main Roads Minister Mark Bailey:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This project will make a big difference for motorists, bike riders, pedestrians and public transport users alike, so it’s great to see we’re a step closer to delivery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Feedback from the stakeholder interest group will play a key role during the design period, and help us make sure the road extension meets the needs of local residents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This project is another great example of the Palaszczuk Government’s commitment to making it easier to move around Queensland.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes attributable to Queensland Member for Caloundra Jason Hunt:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’re all about making it as easy as possible to get to and from the Caloundra CBD, which is why it’s so great to see a contractor locked in to deliver road extension.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This project will ease pressure on local roads, as well as the Caloundra Road and Nicklin Way roundabout, reducing travel times in the area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It comes as part of the Palaszczuk Government’s over $3 billion four-year transport and roads plan for the Sunshine Coast, supporting 2,700 good, secure jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’re continuing to deliver for Sunshine Coast residents, helping them spend less time behind the wheel and more enjoying the great Queensland lifestyle.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes attributable to Sunshine Coast Council Division 2 Councillor Terry Landsberg:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This is another way we can collaboratively work with the community and all tiers of government to advance the liveability of the Sunshine Coast in providing a new transport corridor that services our growing community’s needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Community feedback about the impacts of the new transport link on Bicentennial Park is a key design consideration. A review of the link through the park has been undertaken with an intention to reduce the footprint as the project progresses through detailed design. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This project plays an important role in balancing the importance of safety, connectivity and community integration for Caloundra.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quotes attributable to Jackie Steele, member of the stakeholder interest group (and member for Caloundra Residents Association): &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It's great to see the SIG for this project getting off the ground.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"There are many questions and concerns that people have about this project such as how it fits into the bigger picture, and how the benefits of it are achieved while the things important to the community are protected or enhanced in the process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I look forward to actively participating in the SIG in a positive and productive way by sharing information and contributing perspectives from the Caloundra Residents Association membership and broader networks to get the best outcome for the community."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEDIA CONTACT: &lt;/strong&gt;Courtney Thompson - 0433 585 570&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Mark Bailey</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96536</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 02:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>More than 230 companies answer SuperGrid call</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96540</link><description>&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://mmsprodsa.blob.core.windows.net/attachments/59cdd7d7-5ad0-4bc4-81e4-f382ed90cf0f/web-unnamed%20(1).jpg" alt="Deputy Premier Steven Miles at the top of a wind turbine at Kaban Wind Farm in Far North Queensland"&gt;
                &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Queensland is ready for a SuperGrid manufacturing and jobs boom after more than 230 companies registered interest in local renewable-energy supply-chain opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deputy Premier and Minister for State Development Steven Miles said companies from Queensland, interstate and overseas had quickly recognised the potential of Queensland’s energy-system transformation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s only about a month since the Queensland Government announced our Queensland Energy and Jobs Plan and launched our Energy Manufacturing Opportunity Prospectus,” Mr Miles said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Already, more than 230 companies have responded to the prospectus, answering our call to explore the many opportunities ahead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Around half of these, more than 100 companies, are manufacturers wanting to consider the possibilities for building energy equipment and other assets here in Queensland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“These are the companies who will potentially build our new wind turbines, solar panels, batteries, green hydrogen systems, pumped-hydro facilities and energy transmission networks right here in Queensland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Investment in new renewable energy projects over the next 15 years is expected to exceed $62 billion, so it’s an incredible economic opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Because so much of this investment will be procured by Queensland Government Owned Corporations, we will have the chance to direct our purchasing power into local manufacturing and local jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through until 2035, Queensland’s energy transformation will need:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Energy Minister Mick de Brenni said companies had shown great interest in building the manufacturing capacity in Queensland to deliver the SuperGrid.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Companies of all sizes, areas of expertise, and global reach have told us they want to be part of the energy transformation,” Mr de Brenni said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We are bringing back manufacturing to Queensland – from companies in the state looking to expand, to overseas companies looking to move here, there are hundreds of businesses who want to help build the Queensland SuperGrid. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“That includes the supply of raw materials and components needed by manufacturers as well as the goods and services required to assemble, install, operate and maintain energy assets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Our approach is about being builders, not just buyers, and through our Buy Queensland procurement approach, we can aggregate demand for components that have traditionally been wholly imported, and instead start an industrial scale manufacturing revolution.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Miles said companies who had responded to the prospectus were now part of a Queensland Treasury Corporation market-sounding process identifying existing Queensland-based capability and participation readiness as well as manufacturing opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Importantly this process will also convey to government the roles it could play in supporting the industry to bring the local manufacturing opportunities to life.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The information will be reported to government in March 2023 to inform the release of requests for proposal later in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The prospectus remains open for &lt;a href="https://www.statedevelopment.qld.gov.au/industry/manufacturing-queenslands-super-grid-in-queensland"&gt;registrations of interest&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media contact: &lt;/strong&gt;Katharine Wright - 0428 957 903 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Dr Steven Miles</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96540</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 01:56:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Palaszczuk Government to fund new perinatal mental healthcare centre</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96538</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Palaszczuk Government is partnering with Mater Health to deliver a new inpatient mother and baby unit through an Australia-first integrated perinatal mental healthcare centre in South Brisbane.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health Minister Yvette D’Ath said the Palaszczuk Government was providing $7 million in capital funding to support Mater Health convert a former Sisters of Mercy convent to accommodate the new “Catherine’s House” for mothers, babies and families.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government is also providing more than $11 million in annual operational funding to Mater Health to run the new mother and baby unit at Catherine’s House.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Our investment in Catherine’s House will help to meet the ever-growing demand for services from those impacted by perinatal mental health disorders,” the Minister said.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“It will fund eight public inpatient rooms in Catherine’s House where mothers from across Queensland can stay with their babies while receiving treatment for severe perinatal mental health issues.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“This will triple the number of public in-patient beds available in Queensland from four to twelve for mothers and babies in need of specialist mental health treatment.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“The Palaszczuk Government is proud to partner with Mater Health in an Australia-first initiative to provide more mental health treatment and support to those in need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The funding we are providing for Catherine’s House is being delivered through our five-year $1.6 billion mental health plan, &lt;em&gt;Better Care Together&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There’s no better time to reiterate our commitment to mental health than during Perinatal Mental Health Week (6-12 November).”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Mater Chief Executive Officer Dr Peter Steer said Catherine’s House for Mothers, Babies and Families is anticipated to open its doors to patients by mid-2023.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“It has been co-designed by a team of perinatal health practitioners and parents with lived experience of depression, anxiety and other mental health challenges in the first year of their baby’s arrival,” Dr Steer said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Apart from providing a place where parents can stay with their babies while receiving care, Catherine’s House will also provide a parent support centre for mothers and babies up to six months after birth, a home-visiting service, individual and group therapy treatments and private psychiatry and psychology consultations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“As Australia’s largest maternity services provider, these services ensure that the wellbeing of mothers and babies remains at the heart of Mater.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media contact: &lt;/strong&gt;Office Martin Philip - 0407 675 008&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;                     &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Yvette D'Ath</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96538</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Smart ticketing rollout continues as milestone two million trips achieved</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96549</link><description>&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://mmsprodsa.blob.core.windows.net/attachments/195e899a-f72b-4fa1-8e0b-25751f0c1634/web-Tapping%20on%20with%20smart%20watch%20%20at%20Ascot%20Station.jpg" alt="Smart ticketing rollout continues as milestone two million trips achieved"&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Smart Ticketing is continuing to take charge on the rail network, as the rollout spreads to the Doomben and Shorncliffe train lines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adult full fare customers on these lines will be able to use their credit card, debit card, smartphone or smartwatch to pay for their journey from Monday, November 14.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The announcement comes as the system clocks up two million smart ticketing trips since its rollout on the Gold Coast Light Rail network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Member for Sandgate Stirling Hinchliffe said Smart Ticketing would make catching the train even easier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Palaszczuk Government is continuing to invest in better public transport services, and the $371 million Smart Ticketing rollout is an important part of that,” Mr Hinchliffe said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The days of scrambling for change when you accidently leave your Go Card at home are over.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In a big win for convenience, passengers on the Shorncliffe and Doomben lines can now tap on and tap off with a debit card, smartphone or smart watch.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Member for Nudgee, Leanne Linard MP encouraged Shorncliffe line commuters to give the new tech a try.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’ve already seen customers getting onboard with the new technology as it rolls out on other lines across South-East Queensland,” Ms. Linard said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s great that our part of Brisbane will now join the successful trial. This technology is modernising how we approach public transport payments, which I know will be a welcome change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The remaining train lines will come online before the end of the year, before we turn our attention to buses and ferries.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transport and Main Roads Minister Mark Bailey said train and tram passengers had welcomed the system in droves, with more than two million trips now taken using smart payments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Two million trips are an outstanding endorsement from our customers,” Minister Bailey said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Smart Ticketing investment has always been a hit on Gold Coast trams, with over 1.7 million trips taken using contactless payment on trams since the launch in December 2020.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“More than 360,000 trips have been taken on heavy rail since the launch a few months ago, and that number continues to grow as we connect more destinations with the Smart Ticketing system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Smart Ticketing is currently available on the Ferny Grove, Springfield, Ipswich/Rosewood, Caboolture, Redcliffe Peninsula and Sunshine Coast (through to Gympie North) rail lines with continued rollout on remaining lines planned for this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I look forward to seeing these numbers rise as the rollout continues, and customers transition to this new way to pay.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remaining lines include Gold Coast, Beenleigh, Airport and Cleveland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Bailey said train users who preferred to pay for their journey with their &lt;em&gt;go&lt;/em&gt; card would be able to continue doing so.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Customers travelling on a child or concession fare should continue to use their &lt;em&gt;go&lt;/em&gt; card for now, as should customers on these lines who are travelling beyond Roma Street station or using a connecting bus service," he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plans for activation of the system on buses and ferries are well underway and will be rolled out in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Head online to the &lt;a href="https://translink.com.au/about-translink/projects-and-initiatives/smart-ticketing"&gt;Translink website&lt;/a&gt;, download the MyTranslink app or call 13 12 30 for more information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast Facts from Translink figures: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEDIA CONTACT: &lt;/strong&gt;Courtney Thompson - 0433 585 570&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Mark Bailey</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96549</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 02:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Business Basic Grants return with $5M to assist Queensland small businesses</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96539</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Palaszczuk Government has announced a new round of its popular Business Basics grants will open soon, with $5 million available to small businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister for Employment and Small Business Di Farmer said the $5000 grants will support business owners to develop their skills and adopt best practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Queensland’s small businesses are a driving force for our communities and economy and we will be allocating $5 million in in this round of grants, so 1000 hardworking Queensland small businesses stand to benefit,” Minister Farmer said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Business Basics grants are an investment in local small businesses; supporting them to improve the foundational skills that will help their day-to-day operations and set them up for future growth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“These grants have proven very popular and were made permanent in this year’s budget.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We have listened to feedback from small businesses on streamlining the application process and make it easier to access.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Grants will be awarded through a two-stage process starting with businesses registering their interest to apply by completing a simple, online form that collects basic business information. Then businesses will be selected by a ballot to complete the remaining application process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This process ensures all small businesses that are interested in this grant have an equal opportunity to apply and reduces the stress from applying as businesses can register their interest at any time once registrations open.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Guidelines for this new round of grants are now available and small businesses are encouraged to put forward registrations of interest in the first stage of the application process after they open on 24 November.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Farmer said it is critical that we make sure our regional small businesses are well supported, which is why around $1.5 million will be allocated to support businesses outside of South East Queensland through this next funding round.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Through the past three completed Business Basics rounds, 4195 grants totalling more than $20.9 million have been awarded so far,” Minister Farmer said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“These grants have supported businesses to upgrade websites, engage a business coach or other professional advice, improve their marketing or other aspects of their operations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Farmer said grants are available for cybersafety training and tools, which is very topical right now given the recent Optus and Medibank data breaches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“More than half the successful applicants in past rounds have aimed to increase their on-line capacity, digital presence and/or cybersecurity capacity. The grant offers small businesses a great opportunity to protect themselves and their customers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Ensuring businesses have the knowledge and confidence they need to improve their operations, flows on to better serve their customers or clients, generates more work for their suppliers and grows their local economies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Small businesses deliver a fantastic range of goods and services across Queensland. So far these grants have gone to the businesses in the Torres Strait, Western Queensland and up and down the coast. They have supported businesses in a range of industries, including engineering and fabrication firms, tourist and hospitality operations and the Royal Theatre Winton,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="_Hlk118886933"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Brisbane-based financial planning company, Financial Priorities received a grant in the last round for a full system audit of processes for cyber security and business continuity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Managing Director Jade Dawson said the grant enabled the company to upskill in the best practices for the safe storage and use of sensitive client information methods to help prevent cyber fraud and data breaches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This will allow us as a company to ensure all existing and new staff are trained to the required level before problems occur, which is essential given the client information we must store to manage their finances” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Farmer said this Business Basic round is part of $39.1 million the Palaszczuk Government has committed over the next four years for small business grants and other support to help small businesses, whether they are just getting up and running, or are more established and are looking to pursue new opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“These are just part of the support the Palaszczuk Government is delivering to develop our small business sector,” Minister Farmer said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Our Business Launchpad is making the pathway to start a business anywhere in the state easier, by identifying the different local, state and federal government requirements entrepreneurs will need to address in different industry areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Mentoring for Growth matches small businesses with volunteer small business experts who provide insights and suggestions on tackling challenges or improving growth and development plans.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Business Queensland website provides a range of information covering starting and running a business, including resources to support mental health among owners and staff.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Registrations of interest for this fourth round of Business Basics Grants will be open from 9am on Thursday 24 November until 11.59pm on Monday 5 December 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eligible businesses who have been successful in the ballot will be invited to submit their funding application from 9am on Monday 12 December 2022 and will have until Monday 23 January 2023 to apply.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Farmer said businesses looking to improve their operations can subscribe to Small Business Connect for updates on the next steps for this round of Business Basics by visiting &lt;a href="http://www.business.qld.gov.au/grants-schedule"&gt;www.business.qld.gov.au/grants-schedule&lt;/a&gt; or calling 1300 654 687.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Di Farmer</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96539</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Driver licence numbers safeguarded by verification change</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96541</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Palaszczuk Government is safeguarding Queensland drivers’ licences, with the introduction of the two-factor verification system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This two-factor verification system was scheduled to be introduced in 2023, but has been expedited following the recent Optus data breach.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This verification takes place through the &lt;a href="https://www.idmatch.gov.au/"&gt;Document Verification Service&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transport and Main Roads Minister Mark Bailey said the extra layer of protection was now in place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Anyone who has applied for a bank account, or new phone plan, will know the usual process for providing your licence number to verify your identity,” Minister Bailey said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Now, you will need to provide the unique card number found on your driver licence as a second step in the verification process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This is similar to the CVV found on the back of your credit and debit card, and makes it an even more secure identity document.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This card number is already in place on Queensland issued licenses but will now be a requirement for identification purposes for banks, telcos and utility providers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’m pleased we could fast track the implementation of this system to better protect Queensland identities from fraud.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What does this mean for those impacted by recent data breaches? Well, it’s good news.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Bailey said majority of Queensland Optus customers only had their licence number compromised, not the card number.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Those impacted who had not provided the card number as well can be assured that this extra security measure will mean the compromised licence number cannot be used for fraudulent activity on its own,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I can appreciate there may be some concerned members of the community who will still want to have their licence number changed, and this option will remain available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Optus data breach has been &lt;s&gt;is&lt;/s&gt; a stressful time for many and our staff are pulling out all stops to mange the high volume of requests for new licenses from right across the state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I want to thank TMR staff for their hard work and our customers who have been overwhelmingly patient.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Unlike a driver licence number, the card number will change each time you get a new driver licence card – adding another layer of protection for Queenslanders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Your driver licence should only be used by you, and this new system goes a long way to ensuring that.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over 170,000 Queenslanders had already applied for a new driver licence number since 28 September 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I encourage everyone to stay cyber-alert and vigilant to suspicious activity. I also implore Queenslanders impacted to access the free credit monitoring service provided by Optus,” Mr Bailey said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;a href="https://urldefense.com/v3/__https:/linkprotect.cudasvc.com/url?a=https*3a*2f*2ftmr.qld.gov.au&amp;amp;c=E,1,ZNsQcJJSbJu3crCnNZz7UZwITZa_-oHqfVybq-S2boZounivM_YZmlN4w6obluOOK3px0IszmjS5QgaujjgC9GILKwqpB0b_lJ-K_zUixI1yelgaX_sr&amp;amp;typo=1&amp;amp;ancr_add=1__;JSUl!!OMLVqIk!1uFSJtssYUyCjUj7W4jX3SMqMvxWXM-JlJhj4IApTBfI-08Che0kKe-5V1jAYCo1LXIHfmxHxo52WXoZS5NGxh5lFza3G525Q6ETbqkFRjhP%24"&gt;tmr.qld.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MEDIA CONTACT: &lt;/strong&gt;Courtney Thompson - 0433 585 570&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Mark Bailey</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96541</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 02:40:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New events to showcase Queensland’s multiculturalism in 2023</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96547</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Queenslanders are once again set to celebrate the state’s diversity next year with 117 events and festivals receiving a share of $897,000 in grant funding.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister for Multicultural Affairs Leanne Linard said the latest Celebrating Multicultural Queensland funding round will see some old favourites return, as well as some brand-new events.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’m delighted to announce the Polynesian and African Multicultural event will make its debut in 2023 in the Ipswich region, as well as the Flourish Festival in Emerald, which will celebrate the area’s culture and diversity,” Ms Linard said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Queensland All Nations Touch Football Tournament is also sure to be a wonderful event, engaging people from culturally diverse backgrounds and the wider community through the power of sport, cultural performances and food stalls.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ms Linard said over the past two years Queenslanders had spent a lot of time in isolation due to COVID-19 and the need to connect, share and celebrate the state’s different cultures was more important than ever.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Celebrating our cultural diversity in Queensland is not only important for our social wellbeing, but it also helps promote inclusion and social cohesion,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“From the tip of the state to the south-east corner, there will be plenty of opportunities to get involved.  I encourage everyone to find something that interests them and attend.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“These events are a fantastic way to demonstrate how everybody has a role to play in helping people to connect, contribute and belong.  They enable us all to learn more about the rich diversity in our communities and enhance Queensland’s great lifestyle.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Celebrating Multicultural Queensland program supports events and projects through annual grant funding rounds. A total of 117 events will receive funding ranging from $1000 to $20,000 in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information about the Celebrating Multicultural Queensland program and successful applicants visit &lt;a href="www.cyjma.qld.gov.au/cmq-program"&gt;www.cyjma.qld.gov.au/cmq-program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Contact: Catherine Baker, Senior Media Advisor, tel: 0498 844 783&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Leanne Linard</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96547</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>$10 million to make North Queensland communities safer, stronger and more resilient</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96545</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name="_Hlk118804793"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The Queensland Government will provide $10 million towards 22 council projects aiming to reduce disaster risk and lower insurance costs for residents, businesses and communities in North Queensland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deputy Premier and Minister responsible for the Queensland Reconstruction Authority Steven Miles said a broad range of projects had been approved in the first ever North Queensland Natural Disasters Mitigation Program. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Communities in North and Far North Queensland face significant risks from cyclones, flooding and storm surges and these projects will help reduce the risk posed by these events and make insurance more affordable,” Mr Miles said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Queensland has been hit by almost 100 natural disasters in the past decade and they are becoming more frequent and more intense, so we need to become more innovative in our approach to reduce risk to make our communities safer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Projects include a $2 million investment to fund sand replenishment and extra rock protection on Woodgate Beach in the Bundaberg local government area to provide an extra layer of defence for homes and infrastructure close to the water.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quotes attributable to the Member for Cook Cynthia Lui: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“More than $2 million will go towards a series of projects, which will see the installation of rock protection along the banks of Magnificent Creek in the Kowanyama Aboriginal Shire Council area to help prevent erosion and scouring,” Ms Lui said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Torres Shire Council will receive $857,000 to realign stormwater drainage in four locations to mitigate the effects of flooding.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The appointment of a Coastal Hazard Resilience Officer at Torres Strait Island Regional Council will also help to identify other risks and how to go about lessening their impact.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quotes attributable to the Member for Mackay Julieanne Gilbert: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Mackay Regional Council will receive almost $400,000 towards the investigation, design and modelling of a levee system to reduce inundation during storm surges,” Mrs Gilbert said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Palaszczuk Government is committed to building safer, stronger and more resilient communities and this program is another example of that.”  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quotes attributable to the Member for Gladstone Glenn Butcher:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“After significant rainfall, we do see the Boyne River quickly rise and cause flooding,” Mr Butcher said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We will invest $120,000 for Gladstone Regional Council to engage a consultant to undertake a flood study for the Boyne River catchment area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This will ensure we’re better informed and more prepared to respond to flooding in the future.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quotes attributable to Member for Townsville Scott Stewart: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Fifty low cost water level sensors will be installed at various locations in Townsville to measure water levels in creeks, rivers and drainage channels, thanks to a 125,000 investment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“A $150,000 investment will also see Townsville City Council undertake the detailed design for improvements at Campbell Street Pump Station.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quotes attributable to the Speaker of the Queensland Parliament and Member for Mulgrave Curtis Pitt:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Queensland Government will provide almost $800,000 in funding to Yarrabah Aboriginal Shire Council to upgrade the overland stormwater infrastructure and road crossings along Buddabadoo Road, as well as undertaking a drainage and flood study across the Shire,” Mr Pitt said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This will help improve road safety after flooding and identify future upgrades that will make Yarrabah community more storm resilient”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quotes attributable to the Member for &lt;/em&gt;Rockhampton Barry O’Rourke:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We want to make our communities even more resilient to natural disasters but planning and knowing more about local flooding,” Mr O’Rourke said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Rockhampton Regional Council will receive $350,000 to develop two Floodplain Risk Management Studies in the catchments of Moores Creek and South Rockhampton.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Quotes attributable to the Member for Cairns Michael Healy: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Cairns Regional Council will receive funding for flood modelling studies and the design and planning of infrastructure in the Cairns CBD to reduce the impact of localised flooding,’ Mr Healy said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This will help Cairns better respond to flooding in the CBD, helping us to recovery quicker during the wet season.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mr Miles said the program was established in response to the Australian Consumer and Competition Commission’s Northern Australia Insurance Inquiry’s Final Report released in December 2020, which encouraged governments and insurers to identify mitigation works that can help reduce insurance premiums.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Queensland Reconstruction Authority will administer the $10 million North Queensland Natural Disasters Mitigation Program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Projects funded through this program are expected to be delivered by December 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information on the North Queensland Natural Disasters Mitigation Program and the approved projects go to  &lt;a href="https://www.qra.qld.gov.au/resilience"&gt;www.qra.qld.gov.au/NQNDMP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media contact:&lt;/strong&gt;         &lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; Amy Hunter 0423 651 484&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Dr Steven Miles</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96545</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 06:19:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farm safety calendar competition winner from Gold Coast region congratulated</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96517</link><description>&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://mmsprodsa.blob.core.windows.net/attachments/1432e108-7f39-41e0-9186-59b924f35119/web-Frankie%20Terrace_St%20Bernard%20State%20School-1.jpg" alt="Winning artwork by Frankie Terrace, a Year 5 student at St Bernard State School Tamborine Mountain, was selected for the November page of the 2023 Farm safety calendar."&gt;
                &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A student from the Gold Coast region has become one of twelve Queensland kids to be selected as winners of the 2023 Farm safety calendar competition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Artwork by Frankie Terrace from St Bernard State School, Tamborine Mountain was chosen for the November page of the calendar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Queenslanders can order the 2023 Farm safety calendar for free from the Workplace Health and Safety Queensland (WHSQ) website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Industrial Relations Minister Grace Grace said WSHQ was inundated with 1,500 entries from budding young artists this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Farm safety calendar competition is a great way to get kids from all over Queensland thinking about safety at home and in their classrooms,” Ms Grace said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It gives primary school students the opportunity to help spread the word about how to stay safe on farms and rural properties, protecting our great lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Jobs in agriculture are great jobs that provide better services to Queenslanders, and we want to make sure the message is out there: be safe on farms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The standard of artwork over the years has been fantastic, and the latest edition of the calendar is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The competition is a lot of fun, but the safety messages are serious. The agriculture industry employs around three per cent of Queensland workers but accounts for more than 30 per cent of workplace deaths.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The 2023 calendar includes creative and colourful illustrations about electrical safety, animal safety, tractor and machinery safety, quad bike safety, water safety and general health and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The 12 winners will each receive a $250 Visa gift voucher, plus another $500 for their school, with their artwork and safety messages featuring in the calendar.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;30,000 free copies of the 2023 Farm safety calendar will be available for Queenslanders in October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St Bernard State School Acting Principal, Janelle Menzies, said Year 5 student Frankie Terrace’s winning entry supported students to build an awareness of safety risks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We are appreciative of this wonderful and important initiative,” Ms Menzies said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Students have opportunities to share their safety messages to others to build a generation of farm safe students.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can order your free 2023 Farm safety calendar &lt;a href="https://www.worksafe.qld.gov.au/resources/campaigns/farm-safety-calendar-competition/farm-safety-calendar-order-form"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and check out the winning artwork for each month &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/sh/d0oso9iqngj9ggn/AABli2P_ltHT6jJMK2pPBh5ka?dl=0"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winners of the 2023 Farm safety calendar competition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Month&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isabella Gatti&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kolan South State School, Bundaberg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Water safety (flood waters)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matilda Merkel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oakenden State School, Oakenden&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health and wellbeing (healthy meals)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zahra Hill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kilkivan State School, Kilkivan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Electrical safety (overhead powerlines)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blayke Myles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monto State School, Monto&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quad bike safety (children under 16)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Koby Bordic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minimbah State School, Morayfield&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Animal safety (hand washing)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riley Scheuerle&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St Monica’s Primary School, Oakey&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tractor and machinery safety (carrying passengers)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stevie Heumiller&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gindie State School, Gindie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health and wellbeing (sun safety)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jaxton Cox&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elliott Heads State School, Elliott Heads&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tractor and machinery safety (fenced play area)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isabelle Sheridan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St Maria Goretti School, Inglewood&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quad bike safety (helmet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Briella Murphy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prep&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kulpi State School, Kulpi&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Animal safety (training)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Frankie Terrace&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St Bernard State School, Tamborine Mountain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Electrical safety (safety switches)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tasmin Spencer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miriam Vale State School, Miriam Vale&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Water safety (adult supervision)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media contact:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Grace: Bryce Heaton 0434 575 237&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Office of Industrial Relations: 0478 332 200&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Grace Grace</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96517</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:43:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New dawn for New Farm with $20 million in new facilities</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96553</link><description>&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://mmsprodsa.blob.core.windows.net/attachments/417e38f9-76c8-4350-91d1-9548e05cbc87/web-newfarm2.jpg" alt="Education Minister and local Member for McConnel Grace Grace officially opening new facilities at New Farm State School with Principal Dr Carmel McGrath and student leaders Matthew Blackman, Vivienne Holloway and Emma Harding (L-R)"&gt;
                &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Students and staff at New Farm State School are enjoying the better services and great lifestyle provided by new facilities delivered by the Palaszczuk Government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Education Minister and local Member for McConnel Grace Grace today officially opened new buildings at New Farm State School, representing nearly $20 million worth of Palaszczuk Government investment in the school community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This investment has given this grand old school some fantastic state-of-the-art facilities,” Ms Grace said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Palaszczuk Government is committed to providing better services for Queensland’s fastest growing communities, and that’s exactly what we have delivered here at New Farm State School.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This investment supported almost 60 good, secure jobs over the life of the project.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The first new building, a three-storey learning centre, features 12 classrooms, STEM learning spaces, a teacher curriculum development space and basement parking.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The second new building includes new administration spaces, staff offices, a resource centre and an undercroft.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The project commenced in December 2020 and was completed in September this year, supporting Queensland jobs through the height of the COVID pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It has also included some upgrade works on the school’s marvellous ‘Little Farm’, as well as upgrading and expanding the Prep playground.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Little Farm now has an amphitheatre and stage, as well as some lovely landscaping works to make the space more accessible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The playground is bigger and better and just a fantastic play space for New Farm State School’s Preppies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Palaszczuk Government has ensured that as New Farm continues to grow, its great local state school will be able to cater for higher enrolment demand into the future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In the most recent budget we have committed nearly $220 million over two years to build additional classrooms at Queensland schools experiencing similar in-catchment growth.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New Farm State School Principal, Carmel McGrath, said the whole school community was delighted with the new facilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The new buildings are beautiful to look at and are also state-of-the-art educational facilities, giving us new classrooms and other learning and administration spaces,” Dr McGrath said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The students and teachers all absolutely love it and it has given our community such a boost.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Palaszczuk Government is investing a record almost $2 billion on education infrastructure in the most recent state budget.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media contact: &lt;/strong&gt;Bryce Heaton 0434 575 237&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Grace Grace</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96553</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 05:26:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nation leading codes to protect Queensland workers</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96518</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Queensland workers will have some of the strongest protections in the country when it comes to psychological wellbeing and silicosis prevention, thanks to two new codes introduced by the Palaszczuk Government today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Industrial Relations Minister Grace Grace said the new codes of practice would ensure even more Queenslanders have access to good, safe jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Palaszczuk Government has led the nation when it comes to protecting workers, and these two new codes follow in that proud tradition,” Ms Grace said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The legally-enforceable psychosocial code of practice and regulations will directly address psychological health risks at work, which can be anything from exposure to traumatic events to remote or isolated working.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The code will also provide a practical guide to assist employers and workers to understand their rights and responsibilities, after a national review found many employers were unsure of their duties to manage psychological health and safety risks at work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Research has shown that workers benefit from psychologically healthy workplaces through better individual health, increased job satisfaction, commitment, positive attitudes toward self-development, and lower rates of work-related physical injuries.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is estimated psychological health conditions cost Australian workplaces around $11 billion per year, but there is a return on investment of $2.30 in benefits for every dollar spent on minimising these risks at work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dr Kirsten Way, an organisational psychology expert at the University of Queensland, said the code had the potential to make a profound and positive difference to the mental health of Queenslanders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I am so very pleased that this code has now been developed. This is a truly watershed moment.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Grace said the code of practice to tackle silica dust exposure in the construction industry was also an Australian first.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The need to protect workers from silicosis in other industries, particularly construction, became clear while Queensland’s nation-leading stone benchtop code was being developed in 2019,” Ms Grace said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“That is why this code will apply all construction work in Queensland, as well as the manufacturing of materials such as bricks, blocks, tiles, mortar, and concrete.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The new code sets out effective dust controls to prevent or minimise exposure in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This will protect workers from dangerous levels of silica dust and will save lives.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Grace said the landmark regulation changes and codes of practice were developed through extensive consultation with academics, unions, employer organisations, and the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I thank all those involved for helping to make Queensland workers safer.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Office of Industrial Relations will now work with industry and provide education sessions ahead of the codes commencing next year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Managing the Risk of Psychosocial Hazards at Work Code of Practice&lt;/em&gt; will commence on 1 April 2023. The &lt;em&gt;Managing Respirable Crystalline Silica Dust Exposure in Construction and the Manufacturing of Construction Elements Code of Practice&lt;/em&gt; will commence on 1 May 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They can be viewed at &lt;a href="http://www.WorkSafe.qld.gov.au" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;WorkSafe.qld.gov.au&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media contact:&lt;/strong&gt; Kate Talbot, 0439 803 211&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Grace Grace</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96518</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:42:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farm safety calendar competition winner from Mackay region congratulated</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96519</link><description>&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://mmsprodsa.blob.core.windows.net/attachments/88060914-a580-494f-93a7-edcb59eb097b/web-Matilda%20Merkel_Oakenden%20State%20School-1.jpg" alt="Winning artwork by Matilda Merkel, a Year 6 student at Oakenden State School, was chosen for the February page of the 2023 Farm safety calendar."&gt;
                &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A student from the Mackay region has become one of twelve Queensland kids to be selected as winners of the 2023 Farm safety calendar competition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Artwork by Matilda Merkel from Oakenden State School – a school of just 14 students – was chosen for the February page of the calendar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Queenslanders can order the 2023 Farm safety calendar for free from the Workplace Health and Safety Queensland (WHSQ) website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Industrial Relations Minister Grace Grace said WSHQ was inundated with 1,500 entries from budding young artists this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Farm safety calendar competition is a great way to get kids from all over Queensland thinking about safety at home and in their classrooms,” Ms Grace said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It gives primary school students the opportunity to help spread the word about how to stay safe on farms and rural properties, protecting our great lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Jobs in agriculture are great jobs that provide better services to Queenslanders, and we want to make sure the message is out there: be safe on farms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The standard of artwork over the years has been fantastic, and the latest edition of the calendar is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The competition is a lot of fun, but the safety messages are serious. The agriculture industry employs around three per cent of Queensland workers but accounts for more than 30 per cent of workplace deaths.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The 2023 calendar includes creative and colourful illustrations about electrical safety, animal safety, tractor and machinery safety, quad bike safety, water safety and general health and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The 12 winners will each receive a $250 Visa gift voucher, plus another $500 for their school, with their artwork and safety messages featuring in the calendar.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;30,000 free copies of the 2023 Farm safety calendar will be available for Queenslanders in October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oakenden State School Principal, Angela Wood, said it meant a lot to her small school that Year 6 student Matilda Merkel had won.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It demonstrates to our students and community members that just because you are from a small school, doesn’t mean you can’t do amazing things and change the world,” Ms Wood said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Our school and community are so very proud of Matilda, and so grateful that our school and local community will be represented on the big stage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The money will go a long way in helping us provide extra classroom resources to further our students learning.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can order your free 2023 Farm safety calendar &lt;a href="https://www.worksafe.qld.gov.au/resources/campaigns/farm-safety-calendar-competition/farm-safety-calendar-order-form"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and check out the winning artwork for each month &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/sh/d0oso9iqngj9ggn/AABli2P_ltHT6jJMK2pPBh5ka?dl=0"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winners of the 2023 Farm safety calendar competition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Month&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isabella Gatti&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kolan South State School, Bundaberg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Water safety (flood waters)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matilda Merkel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oakenden State School, Oakenden&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health and wellbeing (healthy meals)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zahra Hill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kilkivan State School, Kilkivan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Electrical safety (overhead powerlines)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blayke Myles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monto State School, Monto&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quad bike safety (children under 16)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Koby Bordic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minimbah State School, Morayfield&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Animal safety (hand washing)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riley Scheuerle&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St Monica’s Primary School, Oakey&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tractor and machinery safety (carrying passengers)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stevie Heumiller&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gindie State School, Gindie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health and wellbeing (sun safety)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jaxton Cox&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elliott Heads State School, Elliott Heads&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tractor and machinery safety (fenced play area)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isabelle Sheridan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St Maria Goretti School, Inglewood&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quad bike safety (helmet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Briella Murphy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prep&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kulpi State School, Kulpi&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Animal safety (training)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Frankie Terrace&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St Bernard State School, Tamborine Mountain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Electrical safety (safety switches)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tasmin Spencer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miriam Vale State School, Miriam Vale&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Water safety (adult supervision)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media contact:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Grace: Bryce Heaton 0434 575 237&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Office of Industrial Relations: 0478 332 200&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Grace Grace</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96519</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extension of handheld metal detection trial to support safer Queensland streets</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96508</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Palaszczuk Government will extend and expand a nation-leading trial to detect weapons and combat violence in the state’s Safe Night Precincts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of the Palaszczuk Government’s commitment to deliver better services and keep Queenslanders safe, the Queensland Police Service trial of “wanding” powers will be extended for two years and expanded to all Safe Night Precincts, public transport modes and associated public transport infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Australian-first trial started on the Gold Coast in May 2021, and resulted in almost 500 offenders charged.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Ryan welcomed the extension of the trial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I fundamentally believe that these powers will save lives and reduce violence on our streets,” Minister Ryan said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Palaszczuk Government is committed to keeping Queenslanders safe. That is why we are always looking at ways to provide our police with stronger legislation, and better tools and resources to do their jobs, and better protect the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Government will continue to work hand in hand with the QPS to keep crime off our streets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I acknowledge the dedicated work of Brett and Belinda Beasley, from the Jack Beasley Foundation, for their fierce advocacy around the extension of wanding powers to assist the QPS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I also acknowledge the work of the QPS and the Queensland Police Union, who have worked with officers on the Gold Coast throughout this trial.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Gold Coast Safe Night Precinct trial resulted in 197 weapons being seized and almost 16,800 people wanded.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Weapons included knives, knuckle dusters, a screw driver, and an axe.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Ryan said the results highlighted the success of wanding in leading to fewer weapons on Queensland streets, while Acting Deputy Police Commissioner Mark Wheeler said QPS officers were looking forward to the trial’s extension.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This is something the Queensland Police Service has asked the Government for, and we will work carefully with the State Government during the extension of this trial,” Deputy Commissioner Wheeler said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There is no need for any person to be in possession of any weapon at any time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Anyone who brings a weapon of any description into a public place should expect to be approached by police.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The message is clear – do not go into public with any object that can be used as a weapon.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is expected the extension of powers will be rolled out early next year. Along with the Gold Coast, wanding will be extended into Safe Night Precincts in:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Contacts&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Minister Ryan’s office: 3035 8300&lt;br&gt;Police Media: 3015 2444&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Mark Ryan</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96508</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 01:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Farm safety calendar competition winner from Sunshine Coast region congratulated</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96520</link><description>&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img class="img-responsive center-block" src="https://mmsprodsa.blob.core.windows.net/attachments/c1ffcdf1-4410-4f2d-b75f-f34ce6bb9c04/web-Zahra%20Hill_Kilkivan%20State%20School-1.jpg" alt="Winning artwork by Zahra Hill, a Year 1 student from Kilkivan State School, was selected for the March page of the 2023 Farm safety calendar."&gt;
                &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A student from the Sunshine Coast region has become one of twelve Queensland kids to be selected as winners of the 2023 Farm safety calendar competition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Artwork by Zahra Hill from Kilkivan State School was chosen for the March page of the calendar.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Queenslanders can order the 2023 Farm safety calendar for free from the Workplace Health and Safety Queensland (WHSQ) website.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Industrial Relations Minister Grace Grace said WSHQ was inundated with 1,500 entries from budding young artists this year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Farm safety calendar competition is a great way to get kids from all over Queensland thinking about safety at home and in their classrooms,” Ms Grace said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It gives primary school students the opportunity to help spread the word about how to stay safe on farms and rural properties, protecting our great lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Jobs in agriculture are great jobs that provide better services to Queenslanders, and we want to make sure the message is out there: be safe on farms.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The standard of artwork over the years has been fantastic, and the latest edition of the calendar is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The competition is a lot of fun, but the safety messages are serious. The agriculture industry employs around three per cent of Queensland workers but accounts for more than 30 per cent of workplace deaths.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The 2023 calendar includes creative and colourful illustrations about electrical safety, animal safety, tractor and machinery safety, quad bike safety, water safety and general health and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The 12 winners will each receive a $250 Visa gift voucher, plus another $500 for their school, with their artwork and safety messages featuring in the calendar.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;30,000 free copies of the 2023 Farm safety calendar will be available for Queenslanders in October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kilkivan State School Principal, Georgia Fleming, said the school community was very excited to hear Year 1 student Zahra Hill had won.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Farm safety calendar competition is extremely relevant for children living on farms in the Kilkivan area,” Ms Fleming said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Promoting farm safety in our community is of high importance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We look forward to giving the children the opportunity to help decide what resources we should buy with the prize money.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can order your free 2023 Farm safety calendar &lt;a href="https://www.worksafe.qld.gov.au/resources/campaigns/farm-safety-calendar-competition/farm-safety-calendar-order-form"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and check out the winning artwork for each month &lt;a href="https://www.dropbox.com/sh/d0oso9iqngj9ggn/AABli2P_ltHT6jJMK2pPBh5ka?dl=0"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winners of the 2023 Farm safety calendar competition:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Month&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Winner &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;School&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theme&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;January&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isabella Gatti&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kolan South State School, Bundaberg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Water safety (flood waters)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matilda Merkel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oakenden State School, Oakenden&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health and wellbeing (healthy meals)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;March&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zahra Hill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kilkivan State School, Kilkivan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Electrical safety (overhead powerlines)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blayke Myles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Monto State School, Monto&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quad bike safety (children under 16)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Koby Bordic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minimbah State School, Morayfield&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Animal safety (hand washing)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;June&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Riley Scheuerle&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;6&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St Monica’s Primary School, Oakey&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tractor and machinery safety (carrying passengers)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stevie Heumiller&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Gindie State School, Gindie&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Health and wellbeing (sun safety)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;August&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jaxton Cox&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Elliott Heads State School, Elliott Heads&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tractor and machinery safety (fenced play area)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;September&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isabelle Sheridan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;4&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St Maria Goretti School, Inglewood&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quad bike safety (helmet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;October&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Briella Murphy&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prep&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kulpi State School, Kulpi&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Animal safety (training)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Frankie Terrace&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;5&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;St Bernard State School, Tamborine Mountain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Electrical safety (safety switches)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tasmin Spencer&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;3&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Miriam Vale State School, Miriam Vale&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Water safety (adult supervision)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media contact:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Grace: Bryce Heaton 0434 575 237&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Office of Industrial Relations: 0478 332 200&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Grace Grace</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96520</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:51:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>NORTH QLD FLOOD WARNING INFRASTRUCTURE NETWORK PROJECT COMPLETE</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96523</link><description>&lt;p&gt;An $8 million project to upgrade North Queensland’s flood warning network is now complete with 180 new flood warning assets installed across 28 council areas in the Far North, North and North West of the state. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Federal Minister for Emergency Management, Senator the Hon Murray Watt said the Flood Warning Infrastructure Network (FWIN) project, made possible through the joint Commonwealth-State Disaster Recovery Funding Arrangements (DRFA), will help keep communities safe with timely flood warnings and forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“A third La Niña season means an increased risk of cyclones and flooding across Northern Queensland,” Minister Watt said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“These rain gauges, rain towers, flood warning signs and high-tech cameras at strategic locations support more timely flood warning intelligence.  Data from rain and river gauges will be incorporated into the Bureau of Meteorology's network and will improve forecasts and warnings for primary producers and communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The new assets will increase the resilience of communities vulnerable to flooding, to support the recovery following the 2019 North and Far North Queensland Monsoon Trough.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The project is part of the $242 million DRFA package activated to support people in Queensland’s north.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deputy Premier and Minister Responsible for the Queensland Reconstruction Authority (QRA) Steven Miles said extensive consultation was undertaken within all affected local government areas.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“QRA worked closely with councils, regional organisations of councils, the Bureau of Meteorology, the Department of Transport and Main Roads, Queensland Rail, Sunwater and state agencies, to support the delivery of timely and accurate flood warnings for Queenslanders,” Mr Miles said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The work undertaken for these assets was extensive, including site assessments, surveys, approvals including cultural heritage checks and signoff from each council.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’re committed to ensuring people in flood-prone communities have appropriate warning of flood events and this includes investment in new and upgraded flood warning infrastructure.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There are more than 3,200 rainfall and river gauges across the state informing state-wide flood warnings and forecasts.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The FWIN project has also seen the addition of 59 cameras which along with the new rain gauges and towers are now operational and benefitting communities in the Far North, North West and North Queensland.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Far North Queensland&lt;/strong&gt; received 45 new flood warnings assets benefiting 10 LGAs: Cairns, Cassowary Coast, Cook, Douglas, Lockhart River, Mapoon, Mareeba, Pormpuraaw, Torres Strait Island and Wujul Wujul.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;North West Queensland&lt;/strong&gt; received 74 flood warning assets, comprising 67 new assets and 7 asset upgrades, benefiting 12 LGAs: Boulia, Burke, Carpentaria, Cloncurry, Croydon, Diamantina, Etheridge, Flinders, Longreach, McKinlay, Richmond and Winton.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;North Queensland &lt;/strong&gt;received 61 new flood warning assets benefiting six LGAs: Burdekin, Charters Towers, Mackay, Hinchinbrook, Townsville and Whitsunday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new rainfall and river height gauge infrastructure conforms to the National Flood Warning Infrastructure Standard and aligns with the Queensland Strategic Flood Warning Infrastructure Plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information visit &lt;a href="http://www.qra.qld.gov.au/fwin"&gt;www.qra.qld.gov.au/fwin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Link to video by QRA: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Qdq7FA81Uo"&gt;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=3Qdq7FA81Uo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media contact:&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Minister Watt: Tali Eley 0499 770 772&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Deputy Premier: Amy Hunter 0423 651 484&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Dr Steven Miles</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96523</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 02:24:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>State funds help restore soils, native vegetation</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96526</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Organisations from the Gulf to Goondiwindi will use more than $11 million in Palaszczuk Government funding over two years to improve soils and farming practices and build up native vegetation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Resources Minister Scott Stewart today announced funds for 17 organisations to work with farmers, graziers, Traditional Owners and their local communities on activities ranging from gully repair to fencing off and protecting native vegetation on stream banks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The condition of our soil and our native plants and trees is critical to Queensland’s food and fibre, resources and tourism industries and the good jobs they generate,” Mr Stewart said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The Palaszczuk Government is committed to supporting regional Queensland jobs and it’s great lifestyle, which is why we’re investing in sustainable agricultural practices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We understand how important sustainable agricultural practices are to our regions, and this funding will go towards reducing over-grazing and boosting native vegetation.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The funds are the first instalment of a Budget commitment of $40 million over four years to increase the potential of the state’s natural resources and promote economic benefits in regional communities&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recipients include land care organisations from Brisbane-based Healthy Land and Water to Southern Gulf NRM at Mount Isa and the Macintyre Agricultural Alliance in Goondiwindi on the Queensland-New South Wales border.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Funds are also going towards training about 38,000 natural resources management volunteers and paid staff involved in these organisations across the state. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’re tapping into local knowledge in local groups because time and again this has proven to deliver the best results for our natural resources,” Mr Stewart said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“A big part of their work is improving farmers’ and graziers’ knowledge of more innovative and sustainable land management practices, like grazing rotation and new monitoring technology, so they can continue to create good jobs and economic benefit for their regional communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“These funds will also help farmers and graziers involve Traditional Owners, so that their valuable traditional knowledge can be incorporated.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.business.qld.gov.au/running-business/environment/natural-resource-funding#:~:text=The%20Natural%20Resources%20Recovery%20Program,and%20innovation%20for%20land%20resources."&gt;More information on the funding is available online.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;lt;ENDS&amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Scott Stewart</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96526</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 03:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Queensland Police Service leading the way in greening their fleet</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96529</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Palaszczuk Government continues to lead the way in clean, green, renewable energy, today announcing 100 percent of the Queensland Police Service’s operational SUV and sedans will be hybrid models within two years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As Queensland works to achieve 70 percent renewable energy by 2032, the QPS is powering toward a fully hybrid or plug-in hybrid SUV and sedan fleet, with almost three quarters of all operational vehicles now environmentally responsible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police Minister Mark Ryan said in the past three years the QPS has steadily been growing the number of fuel-efficient hybrids and plug-in hybrids in operation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I am proud to advise that as of today, a remarkable 71 percent of police sedans and SUVs are now low emission hybrid vehicles,” Minister Ryan said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Police will be adopting a ‘hybrid first’ policy for its sedans and SUV fleet, and will progressively replace all non-hybrids with new, more efficient hybrid vehicles,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We will always provide the very best tools and technology to our police, and today’s announcement is just another example of the Palaszczuk Government’s commitment to give our dedicated officers the greatest equipment available.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The announcement sees the QPS lead the way among all Australian policing agencies when it comes to the planning of a environmentally responsible fleet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Acting Deputy Commissioner Mark Wheeler said QPS vehicles collectively clocked up around 1.5 million kilometres each week travelling across the vast state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The very nature of operational policing means our officers are constantly on the move,” Acting Deputy Commissioner Wheeler said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We know the vehicles must be fit for purpose, reliable and able to be used in challenging circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We are aiming to achieve a 100 percent hybrid sedan and SUV fleet within two years, subject to supply constraints and operational requirements.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This is not only extremely important for the environment in terms of reducing emissions, but also helps to offset the rises in fuel and operational costs we are all experiencing,” he said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The QPS will look to capitalise on its substantial rooftop solar assets as it moves towards a full electric vehicle future in the years to come.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast facts:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Media contacts  &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minister Ryan’s Office:                                                                     Ph: (07) 3035 8300&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Police Media:                                                                                     Ph: (07) 3015 2444&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Mark Ryan</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96529</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 22:43:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Queensland's screen industry continues to thrive</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96533</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It was another bumper year for film and television production in Queensland, with a new report confirming the state’s screen industry continues to shine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Screen Australia’s Drama Report 2021­–22 was released today and shows Queensland’s screen industry contributed $465 million to the local economy in the last year including hosting four international productions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Premier said the result continued momentum from last year’s record expenditure in the state, largely due to Queensland’s pandemic measures, and was the second highest result over a five-year period.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“As the sunshine state opened up from the pandemic, its reputation as an ideal filming destination — backed by a winning combination of incentives, crews, locations and facilities — contributed to a pipeline of feature films like &lt;em&gt;Ticket to Paradise, Wizards! &lt;/em&gt;and sci-fi series &lt;em&gt;Nautilus&lt;/em&gt; flocking to Queensland, as did homegrown series including &lt;em&gt;Upright&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Darby and Joan,”&lt;/em&gt; the Premier said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Queensland rode the wave of record-breaking investment in Australian drama by streaming services, with Screen Queensland supporting projects from Netflix, Stan, Disney+, Paramount+, Amazon and more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Netflix alone produced four titles in Queensland — &lt;em&gt;Boy Swallows Universe&lt;/em&gt; which is currently in production&lt;em&gt;, Irreverent, A Perfect Pairing &lt;/em&gt;and &lt;em&gt;True Spirit&lt;/em&gt;."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Premier said the Queensland Government’s enhanced Post, Digital and Visual Effects (PDV) incentive ensured Queensland was well-positioned to capitalise on the increase in post-production opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a name="_Hlk118911755"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;The PDV incentive has resulted in Screen Queensland securing an unprecedented number of projects for the state, injecting more than $38.5 million to the local economy,” the Premier said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Within the first 12 months of the increased incentive, 20 projects were confirmed for Queensland post-production facilities across a variety of services including visual effects, animation, editing and sound — boosting Queensland Production Expenditure by 270 per cent since 2019–20.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Offering the most competitive PDV incentive on the east coast of Australia at 15 per cent has stimulated unparalleled growth in just 12 months — supporting 13 local businesses, growing employment opportunities and generating millions for the Queensland economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Queensland has a long-held reputation as a destination of choice for filmmakers and by supporting the state’s PDV capabilities, our government is keeping Queensland top of mind as a complete end-to-end home for screen production.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Local post-production houses such as The Post Lounge, Pixel Zoo, Fika Entertainment and Serve Chilled have all capitalised on the growth of the PDV incentive to secure work with some of the world’s leading film and television studios. South Australia’s Rising Sun Pictures has established a new studio in Brisbane, quickly achieving a full production slate in a facility designed to accommodate up to 60 creatives. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the secured projects is the Paramount+ 10-part series adaptation of the Australian bestselling book, &lt;em&gt;Last King of the Cross &lt;/em&gt;— produced by Sydney’s Helium, with post-production by Brisbane facility Chop Shop Post.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mark Fennessy, Co-founder and Chairman of Helium, said that the changes to Queensland’s PDV incentive created a compelling drawcard, making Queensland a top choice for both cost-effectiveness and expertise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Screen Queensland’s PDV financial incentive is a welcome added bonus to a production as large in visual scale as Helium’s&lt;em&gt; Last King of The Cross,” &lt;/em&gt;said Fennessy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;“Choosing Chop Shop Post to manage the visual effects across the series, both on set and in post-production, was an easy decision to make, as not only does their reputation precede them, but they work to budget, deliver clear and practical feedback about how to get the greatest visuals on screen, and intuitively problem-solve with a creative edge.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lav Bodnaruk, Co-Owner and Executive Producer of Chop Shop Post said the company is proud to be working with Helium on &lt;em&gt;Last King of the Cross,&lt;/em&gt; with the enhanced incentive proving to be a vital investment in the local screen sector.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Kudos to Screen Queensland for their foresight in offering a PDV incentive that moves with the times, supporting Queensland’s agile post-production companies to work on such world class productions,” said Bodnaruk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Screen Queensland is supporting the PDV boom by facilitating year-long, full-time paid placements with several leading facilities in Queensland and continuing its successful attachments program for early-career practitioners on agency-supported productions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRODUCTIONS SUPPORTED IN 2021–22 FINANCIAL YEAR VIA SCREEN QUEENSLAND’S &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;POST, DIGITAL AND VISUAL EFFECTS (PDV) INCENTIVE&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Baby Alive!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; Season 2 (eOne Entertainment, Hasbro Australia)&lt;br&gt;Pixel Zoo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Bachelor Australia &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Season 10 (Warner Bros. International Television Production Australia)&lt;br&gt;Freelance Queensland editors&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Greatest Surf Movie in The Universe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Bronte Pictures)&lt;br&gt;The Post Lounge&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Beyond the Reef &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;(The Steve Jaggi Company and In Three Production)&lt;br&gt;Serve Chilled&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Cost &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;(Bronte Pictures)&lt;br&gt;The Post Lounge&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dark Harvest &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;(MGM)&lt;br&gt;Hotel Lima and Wild Things Creative&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dougherty Gang&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Charlie Baby Productions)&lt;br&gt;Serve Chilled&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Foe&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (See-Saw Films)&lt;br&gt;Alt.vfx&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Infernal Machine &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;(Moviebox Limited, Paramount Pictures)&lt;br&gt;Serve Chilled&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Untitled Project&lt;/strong&gt; (Hoodlum Entertainment)&lt;br&gt;Cutting Edge, Unison Sound and freelance post-production crew&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kane&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; (Bronte Pictures)&lt;br&gt;The Post Lounge&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Last King of the Cross &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;(Helium Pictures)&lt;br&gt;Chop Shop&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Post&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;LOL House of Surprises &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;(MGA Entertainment Australia)&lt;br&gt;Pixel Zoo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mattel American Girl: Designer House &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Season 1 (Mattel)&lt;br&gt;Fika Entertainment and Folklore Sound&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rainbow High &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Season 3 (MGA Entertainment Australia)&lt;br&gt;Pixel Zoo&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scarygirl &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;(Like a Photon Creative, Passion Pictures Australia)&lt;br&gt;Cosmic Dino Studio and The Post Lounge&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Teletubbies Let’s Go! &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Season 1 (WildBrain Spark)&lt;br&gt;Fika Entertainment&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Two untitled U.S. projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;Rising Sun Pictures&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Untitled Project&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fika Entertainment and Folklore Sound&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;ENDS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media contact:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zoe Russell (Premier's office) - 0439 982 347&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amanda Lawson (Screen Queensland) - 07 3248 0535 &lt;a href="mailto:media@screenqld.com.au"&gt;media@screenqld.com.au&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Annastacia Palaszczuk</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96533</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 23:47:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government to continue tackling domestic violence following QAO Report</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96532</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Palaszczuk Government has welcomed the Queensland Audit Office report, &lt;em&gt;Keeping People Safe from Domestic and Family Violence. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister for Women and the Prevention of Domestic and Family Violence, Shannon Fentiman, said that the Government was proud of its track record in addressing domestic and family violence (DFV).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We remain committed to doing everything we can to keep women and girls safe,” Minister Fentiman said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Government will be accepting all of the report’s recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Since the Audit Office began this report, the Palaszczuk Government has embarked on an ambitious and ground-breaking path towards ending domestic and family violence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We have established the independent Women’s Safety and Justice Taskforce to make recommendations on how we can best reform our systems to better protect victims and hold perpetrators to account.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In response to the 89 recommends from the Taskforce’s first report, &lt;em&gt;Hear her voice&lt;/em&gt;, the Government committed an historic $363 million package of reforms.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This means since 2015, the Palaszczuk Government has invested almost $1 billion into tackling domestic and family violence.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Minister also said the Government this week announced an additional $1 million every year to further support existing High-Risk Teams across the state.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We know that the eight operational High-Risk Teams are saving lives, and this money will help further support the vital work they do,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I note that many of the Audit Office’s recommendations overlap with recommendations from the Women’s Safety and Justice Taskforce. This includes more integrated response, better training, and more information sharing.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“This Government has acted strongly, decisively, and has made decisions based on the evidence and experiences of victims who have bravely told their stories,” the Minister said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The report also follows the Government’s establishment of a Commission of Inquiry into Police responses to DFV, which will be handing its recommendations in the coming weeks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ends&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media contact: Clare Barnes 0497 829 747&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Shannon Fentiman</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96532</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 23:40:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Support for Queensland veterans boosted by new council</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96534</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Thousands of current and ex-service personnel will have a stronger voice through the new Queensland Veterans’ Council.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On the eve of Remembrance Day, Premier Annastacia Palaszczuk said the Queensland Veterans’ Council would shine a light on Queensland’s veterans’ community and improve their access to Government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Council will have direct access to my Government, to provide advice on matters affecting veterans throughout the State,” the Premier said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The members appointed to the Council bring a wealth of experience, either as veterans or other members of the veterans’ community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“ They understand the needs of vets and the organisations that support them.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Veterans’ Council members are:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Council also includes two ex-officio members representing the Queensland Government and Brisbane City Council.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Assistant Minister to the Premier for Veterans’ Affairs Bart Mellish said the new statutory body would strengthen support for current and ex-service personnel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Council will be at the heart of matters relating to our veterans and the ex-service organisations supporting them in the community,” Mr Mellish said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Premier and I will be in regular contact with the Council and welcome the opportunity to receive advice and engage in discussions to enhance the lives and support of Queensland’s veterans.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Queensland Veterans’ Council is supported by the Veterans’ Reference Group, which will advise Council, consult with the veterans’ community, and help Council advise the Premier.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Media contact – Lane Calcutt 0411535191&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Annastacia Palaszczuk &amp; Mr Bart Mellish</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96534</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 23:52:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Focus on growth during Indigenous Business Month</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96527</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Queensland’s 2022 Indigenous Business Month has been hailed a success, with greater recognition for Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander owned businesses and more than 60 events held across the state throughout October.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Small Business Minister Di Farmer said the eighth annual Indigenous Business Month focused on partnerships and growth through its theme &lt;em&gt;‘&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;Actions Today. Impact Tomorrow’.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Indigenous Business Month involved exciting celebrations and valuable networking events from Thursday Island to Mount Isa and from Cairns to Coolangatta,” Ms Farmer said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“There were ‘meet the buyer and seller’ networking events, mentoring and capability building sessions, and Indigenous Business Connect networking events that focused on procurement and supply chain opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Government was also pleased to announce Deadly Business 2032 during Indigenous Business Month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Deadly Business 2032 is a key project for the Far North region that will facilitate new partnerships, prepare businesses and generate business growth in the lead up to the Brisbane 2032 Olympic and Paralympic Games,” Minister Farmer said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“First Nations businesses employ more First Nations workers than any other businesses, so it’s important to continue to support Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander owned businesses to grow.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Partnerships Minister Craig Crawford said the Palaszczuk Government is continuing to create good First Nations jobs, open up new First Nations business opportunities, and grow the economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We know there are many Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander owned businesses that have the capacity to successfully supply the quality goods and services our state needs,” Mr Crawford said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The &lt;a href="https://www.dsdsatsip.qld.gov.au/resources/dsdsatsip/work/atsip/business-economic-development/qipp/queensland-indigenous-procurement-policy.pdf"&gt;Queensland Indigenous (Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander) Procurement Policy&lt;/a&gt; (QIPP) helps stimulate entrepreneurship and business ownership through more opportunities for First Nations owned businesses to supply to government – and we are seeing results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In the 2021- 2022, 535 Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander owned businesses supplied $440 million in goods and services to the Queensland Government, up from $322 million for the 2020- 2021 financial year.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Crawford said the excellence of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander owned businesses was on show at the annual Buy Queensland awards this month.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The &lt;a href="https://www.epw.qld.gov.au/about/strategy/buy-qld/engage/buy-queensland-supplier-awards"&gt;Buy Queensland awards&lt;/a&gt; recognise outstanding businesses who are supplying to the Queensland Government,” Mr Crawford said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Of the four awards available, three were won by Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander owned businesses, and a further three First Nations-owned businesses were highly commended.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I especially want to highlight the achievements of the 100 per cent Indigenous owned, and women-led Iscariot Media who won the Diversity through Supply Chains Award.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Iscariot Media is a great example of a business, who through their supply chains and other sourcing activities, support social outcomes with staff in Cairns, Moreton, Logan and Brisbane.’’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister Farmer said in Far North Queensland, First Nations company, Jumbun Limited, was recognised at the 19&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; annual Cassowary Awards for helping to protect the Wet Tropics World Heritage Area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Jumbun won the People Country Culture award for &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Gumbadda in our Mala,&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; meaning Cyclone in our Hands, a transformative program co-funded by the Palaszczuk Government,” Minister Grace said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We are excited for more Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander owned businesses to enjoy the success of businesses like Iscariot Media and Jumbun Limited.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Other highlights of Indigenous Business Month included events such as Black Coffee, Business Ready, Growing Indigenous Business and Yarning2032 on the Darling Downs, which provided opportunities for conversations and partnerships.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“On the Sunshine Coast, Blak Markets showcased more than 20 different Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander owned businesses selling their products.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“In Townsville there was a range of events including an Indigenous Women in Business celebration and tender and grant writing workshops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The Queensland Indigenous Business Expo and Forum hosted by the South East Queensland Indigenous Chamber of Commerce was attended by 280 participants,” Minister Farmer said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Following the success of Indigenous Business Month, we look forward to hearing more about how Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander owned businesses are achieving in the lead up to the Brisbane 2032.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ENDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media contact: Peter Michael 0477 948 091&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Craig Crawford</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96527</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Proposals back genuine small-scale miners</title><link>https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96543</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Queensland’s small-scale miners will continue to operate mining claims as a suite of proposals hits the table to support genuine miners.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Resources Minister Scott Stewart said mining claims would remain in the state’s mining laws and a moratorium on new claims would end as scheduled on November 24.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The 12-month moratorium has served its purpose and allowed government to talk to communities, landholders and small-scale miners about the best way forward,” Mr Stewart said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I would particularly like to acknowledge the valuable contribution that Mayor Kerry Hayes and the Central Highlands Regional Council have made throughout this process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We’re proposing a suite of possible changes from these discussions over the past 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Queensland has a long history of small-scale mining, particularly for opals, sapphires and other gemstones in central and western Queensland.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“These proposals aim to back genuine miners as well as delivering for everyone else related to small-scale mining – landholders, local communities, and local businesses.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The proposed changes also aim to address issues for local communities, such as claim holders building permanent structures and living on claims rather than mining them and holders abandoning sites, leaving them for the taxpayer to clean up.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The proposed changes are available in the discussion paper released today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proposals include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The discussion paper also seeks input on how a transition would work for miners with existing mining claims.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Queensland has almost 2000 mining claims, most of them for hand-mining, and about 14 per cent for machinery mining. About 80 per cent of all claims are in the Central Queensland gemfields. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the past year the Queensland Government has also been working with the Central Highlands Regional Council on the joint planning study for the Gemfields region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Consultation on the discussion paper is open until 24 February.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Visit &lt;a href="https://haveyoursay.resources.qld.gov.au/implement-reforms-for-small-scale-mining"&gt;https://haveyoursay.resources.qld.gov.au/implement-reforms-for-small-scale-mining&lt;/a&gt; for more information and details on how to comment on the proposals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[ENDS]&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please use our &lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/contact-us/complaints/"&gt;complaints and compliments form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;© The State of Queensland 1997–2022 (Department of the Premier and Cabinet)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.qld.gov.au/" accesskey="1"&gt;Queensland Government&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>The Honourable Scott Stewart</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://statements.qld.gov.au/statements/96543</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 04:22:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>