<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Tasmanian Labor</title><link>https://taslabor.com/news/</link><description>News and media releases from Tasmanian Labor</description><language>en-AU</language><copyright>Copyright Tasmanian Labor</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 13:00:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Scrapy 2.4.1</generator><item><title>Premier insults Tasmanian school staff</title><link>https://taslabor.com/premier-insults-tasmanian-school-staff/</link><description>&lt;div class="content-body"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Premier Rockliff and Education Minister Roger Jaensch have today continued their shambolic stance on school staff receiving the pay and conditions they need to improve learning. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Premier and Education Minister have both called yesterday’s action ‘irresponsible’ but what is really irresponsible is ignoring workforce pleas to better support Tasmanian students and lift education outcomes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is a government that is incapable of taking responsibility and instead would rather disrespectfully blame hardworking school staff, who are at their wits end.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Premier Rockliff has claimed that Australian Education Union members, who are literally thousands of dedicated school staff, had no right to strike as the next salary increase is not due until March 2023. This is despite Premier Rockliff issuing an ultimatum that negotiations needed to be finalised by 1 December this year. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is blatantly clear that this Premier does not realise that yesterday’s action was about much more than wages, despite teachers, firefighters, health workers and many other public sector workers making that painfully clear.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is a Liberal Government that clearly does not understand the plight of our students and the people educating them. It is well beyond time Premier Rockliff got his priorities right.   &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Josh Willie MLC&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Shadow Minister for Education &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Tasmanian Labor</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://taslabor.com/premier-insults-tasmanian-school-staff/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 04:02:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government agenda in chaos</title><link>https://taslabor.com/government-agenda-in-chaos/</link><description>&lt;div class="content-body"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The Liberal Government has had a chaotic and dysfunctional 2022, with 3 Ministers and a Premier resigning from their positions. This has led to the proroguing of parliament twice in one year – the first time in 40 years.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The impact of the Government’s chaos and dysfunction has been reflected in the weak legislative agenda with, at last count, just 23 bills passed.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As unambitious as the government’s agenda is, even that isn’t being delivered as Parliament has spluttered its way through the year.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Just yesterday the Attorney General had to come back to her own Bill with over 30 different amendments to it. This astounding display on the floor of Parliament highlights the dysfunction of this Liberal Government.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We are on track for the Government to break its record for least number of Bills passed in a non-election year.  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Government has got its priorities completely wrong for Tasmanians. While Tasmanians grapple with a health, housing and cost of living crisis this Government prioritises building a $750 million stadium at Macquarie Point. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dean Winter MP&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Leader of Opposition Business &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Tasmanian Labor</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://taslabor.com/government-agenda-in-chaos/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 04:10:45 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government lets maritime college vessel sink</title><link>https://taslabor.com/government-lets-maritime-college-vessel-sink/</link><description>&lt;div class="content-body"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Whilst the government spruiks its maritime college defence partnerships its commitment to Australian sea farer training is under question as the University of Tasmania has revealed its plans to sell the training vessel ‘Blue Fin’ with no commitment to a replacement vessel.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hot on the heels of losing the Pacific Patrol Boats funding and the sacking of senior academic staff it appears the undermining of this valuable part of Australia’s maritime training continues.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The ability to have onboard experience is a significant drawcard for students to enrol in Launceston to study for careers in the maritime industry.  It provides a practical learning environment in an industry that has identified skill shortages at a time when the need to reinvest in our own supply chain management has become more evident.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Australian trained sea farers have been some of the most respected in the work with international seafarers’ research bodies historically ranking the quality of the training amongst the highest in the world.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The University has failed to satisfactorily explain this cut that will damage our reputation and impact on the training at our AMC.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The government failed to intervene to help save the Pacific Boats contracts, stood back as senior highly skilled staff were made redundant, the question now is will they act now to protect the quality of training and reputation of our maritime college?  Or are they prepared to let that sink?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Michelle O’Byrne MP&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Labor Member for Bass &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Tasmanian Labor</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://taslabor.com/government-lets-maritime-college-vessel-sink/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 03:58:12 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Outpatient plan follows nearly a decade of Liberal failure</title><link>https://taslabor.com/outpatient-plan-follows-nearly-a-decade-of-liberal-failure/</link><description>&lt;div class="content-body"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Today’s announcement that the Liberal Government has finally come up with a plan to address out of control specialist waiting lists is welcome news.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But it is too little, too late for patients who have been waiting years to see specialists. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The fact is under the Liberals the specialist wait list has more than doubled, growing by almost 30,000 people.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Specialist wait times are also completely unacceptable, with urgent neurosurgery patients, who are meant to be seen in 30 days, currently forced to wait &lt;a href="https://www.outpatients.tas.gov.au/clinicians/wait_times/wait_times"&gt;well over two years&lt;/a&gt;. Less urgent neurosurgery patients, meanwhile, wait an average of over six and a half years.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;So while any promises are welcome, what we really need to see is action to undo the damage the Liberals have caused over the past eight years.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Liberals have a track record of making big promises when it comes to health services in Tasmania including a 580-million-dollar redevelopment of the Launceston General Hospital. To date, very little has been funded or delivered. Let’s hope this is not another announcement that goes undelivered.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tasmania’s health system continues to deteriorate under the watch of a part-time Health Minister who is more focused on building a $750 million stadium in Hobart than fixing the state’s health crisis.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Premier Rockliff should appoint a full-time Health Minister and make health a priority for the Liberal Government. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anita Dow MP&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Shadow Minister for Health &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Tasmanian Labor</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://taslabor.com/outpatient-plan-follows-nearly-a-decade-of-liberal-failure/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 04:32:18 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Apology to victims and survivors of child sexual abuse in institutional settings</title><link>https://taslabor.com/apology-to-victims-and-survivors-of-child-sexual-abuse-in-institutional-settings/</link><description>&lt;div class="content-body"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I rise to speak strongly in support of this motion…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Because there is no matter of greater importance than the safety and wellbeing of our children.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And we in the Parliament must acknowledge and take responsibility for the failings in our state’s government institutions which have so badly let down so many children in our schools, hospitals, the youth justice system and other government settings. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker,&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We deeply regret these failings, which have caused enormous pain and suffering to children who should have been afforded the highest protections we can offer – and we offer our deepest and sincerest apologies.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To the children who have grown up with that pain and have had to fight every step of the way to find a path through their trauma, hurt and feelings of betrayal and try to move on with their lives in spite of it – in many cases, with little to guide them but their own courage.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tragically also, to the children who were unable to find a way through – whose pain was too overwhelming for them to overcome – and who are no longer with us as a result.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is nothing that can make up for that but if we are to find a way forward and protect other children, we must start by acknowledging the profound harm these systemic failings have done to so many children.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Children who had their innocence stolen from them and then had to fight a system that didn’t believe them – or that dismissed their complaints because it would be “too hard to prove”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And, to the victims’ and survivors’ families – who entrusted their children’s care to state institutions only for that trust to be betrayed in the worst possible ways.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To the whistle-blowers who weren’t listened to, who had their concerns minimised, who tried to warn us of the horrors but found that instead of our gratitude for helping to protect children they got silenced. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To those parents who saw their children suffering, but were unable to penetrate a wall of deeply held trauma, amid the complex emotions of guilt, shame, anger, and sorrow.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To those who knew and tried to get help for their children – and of course justice – but were unable to penetrate a wall of bureaucracy and were left by the system to deal with their pain, grief, trauma and guilt without the support and help they deserved.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…And without the support and help their children deserved.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To each of you we say sorry. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And we are sorry that we still cannot protect all our children. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We have not done enough yet but let this day be a mark of our public commitment to each of you that we will redouble our effort. And that what follows our words in this place will be action. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Government made a commitment to implement all of the recommendations of the Commission of Inquiry when they are handed down next year and that is a commitment that must be kept. Because while today is about acknowledging and apologising for the way we have let children down there must also be a single-minded focus on doing everything within our power to protect from this failure to keep children safe from happening again.  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I would like to acknowledge former Premier Peter Gutwein who announced the Commission of Inquiry and did so, I believe, from a place of genuine desire to make a difference to the lives of children in our state. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I want to thank the Commissioners for their dedication and careful work and all the staff who have supported the Commission of Inquiry. Their compassion and care has helped to support many victim survivors tell their story and expose the failures of successive governments. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I would like to recognise the bravery of all those who have come forward but in particularly I would like to pay my gratitude to those who spoke up, both on and off the record, before the Commission of Inquiry was announced. Their powerful stories shocked us, horrified us and demanded action from us. And from that the requirement for a Commission of Inquiry became clear.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I know that the wider community shares the distress and sorrow at both the nature and extent of the matters that the Commission of Inquiry has exposed. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We heard the testimony and questioned how these things could have happened. We read the reports in the media and we asked why nobody did anything. But the uncomfortable reality is that many of these failures to protect children were known, but people didn’t act. And many of these stories of abuse have been told before, but people didn’t listen. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Commission of Inquiry has provided a safe place for people to share their experiences and for them to be believed. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some gave evidence to the Commission of Inquiry because they wanted to protect others. They wanted to expose what they had witnessed; the failings, the horror and the lack of action to keep children safe. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some shared stories where the only action that was taken was to protect the perpetrator. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some shared their own stories of abuse. Of their pain. Of how a system that should be set up to protect our most vulnerable utterly failed. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The personal stories from the Commission of Inquiry were the most heartbreaking to hear.  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The horrific abuse children who should have been safe were subjected to and the years and years of dealing with the trauma of that abuse…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…the lifelong damage that has caused.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…the gaslighting – not being believed by people in positions of power. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…holding the pain tight in their chest as it threatened to consume them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…the loneliness, the isolation, the secrets, the shame. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…the horror of discovering through the media that they were not alone – that so many others had experienced similar trauma – in some cases at the hands of the same perpetrator.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…the ordeal of having to speak up themselves through the media in order to finally be heard.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Tragically, these horrific experiences are not restricted to those who took part in the Commission of Inquiry…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There are those who have equally dreadful stories who have never shared them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We know that many other children have also suffered terribly at the hands of people they should have been able to trust.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And in every instance where a child has been abused and had their world shattered it is important to always remember that it is not your fault. It was never your fault. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And we know that all of you who have experienced this terrible betrayal have lived a very different life from the life you should have had.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For all of that, we acknowledge your anguish and pain and are deeply and sincerely sorry. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I want to acknowledge the extraordinary courage and resilience it has taken to come through such a devastating experience.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is your strength and fortitude that has brought us to where we are today – no longer dismissing these awful stories of abuse, but exposing them instead.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…so that the systemic failings that allowed this to go on for so long can be fixed…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…so that those who allowed these atrocities to continue can be held to account…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…so that we can have trust in our public institutions again…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…so that we can know that our children are safe and protected.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…so that this never happens again.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr Speaker, we come together today in this House, to acknowledge the deep hurt caused by these failings…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…to take responsibility for these failings…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…and to give our firm commitment to do better…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We are here as representatives of the Tasmanian community, to offer our sincere apology to the children whose lives were so damaged,&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…to their mothers and fathers, their brothers and sisters, their grandparents and to all that loved them.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I know that for some, today will be met with mixed feelings. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is a highly sensitive and personal issue.  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Every person will deal with this in different ways and it’s important that we respect that. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For some people today will be a really important day to help them heal. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For others, it might be quite a distressing day. And I want to acknowledge that. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That range of reactions is normal and we accept and respect that. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our role is to do everything we can to work with individuals to ensure they have the support they need. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is no apology that can take away the weight you bear, the loss of your innocence or the sadness that remains with you…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;But I hope that by making this apology today, we can help ease the burden of your trauma.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We are deeply sorry. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sorry for your pain.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sorry for your suffering.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Sorry for the appalling treatment you endured after already experiencing one of the worst things a child can experience. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And sorry for failing you when you should have been protected.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;No-one should suffer as you have suffered and along with our sincere apology, we offer you our ongoing compassion and support.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And we offer our vow that we will continue working to ensure that this never happens again…&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;…that Tasmania’s children are protected as they should be – in a community that always puts their safety first. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I commend the motion to the House.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are in distress, please call 1800 MYSUPPORT (1800 697 877)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Or 1800RESPECT (1800 737 732)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Or call Lifeline on 13 11 14&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rebecca White MP   &lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Labor Leader &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Tasmanian Labor</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://taslabor.com/apology-to-victims-and-survivors-of-child-sexual-abuse-in-institutional-settings/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 04:08:57 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Time for Government to cap prices for contracted energy customers</title><link>https://taslabor.com/time-for-government-to-cap-prices-for-contracted-energy-customers/</link><description>&lt;div class="content-body"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Whether you’re a Tasmanian household or business, you should be paying Tasmanian prices for Tasmanian power.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Hundreds of businesses across the State are now in the grips of re-contracting, or preparing to re-contract in an overheated National Energy Market, even though they are based in Australia’s renewable energy heartland. These contracted customers are paying or facing major increases in their energy costs of 50 per cent or more. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is entirely due to the fact the Liberals abandoned their “Tasmania First” energy policy and exposed our state to the chaos in the national market.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is well past time for the Government to implement an energy rebate scheme for large, contracted customers.  We are the only state in the position to do so, with publicly owned generation assets able to protect customers from the impacts of inflated wholesale markets costs.  &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As it did in 2017, the Government should step in and protect Tasmanian businesses from the massive cost increases being experienced. Under the scheme rebates per megawatt hour would be made available to eligible business customers. The rebates should also apply retrospectively to businesses who have already had to re-contract so far this year during this period of price volatility.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Already this year, Tasmanian Labor has tabled and debated legislation that would have capped power prices for Tasmanian households and saved them around $200 this year.  This was based on the same price cap Legislation the Government put in place in 2018. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Every day the government refuses to act, is another day of uncertainty and higher prices that Tasmanians can’t afford.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dean Winter MP&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Shadow Minister for Energy &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Tasmanian Labor</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://taslabor.com/time-for-government-to-cap-prices-for-contracted-energy-customers/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 23:35:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Conversion therapy chaos in Liberal camp</title><link>https://taslabor.com/conversion-therapy-chaos-in-liberal-camp/</link><description>&lt;div class="content-body"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In what turned out to be an astounding interview on ABC radio this morning, Government backbencher and outlier Lara Alexander claimed the Premier Jeremy Rockliff supported her choice to host a forum about upholding the practice of conversion therapy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;When asked whether or not Jeremy Rockliff supports the hosting of this forum, Lara Alexander said, “He supports me having a forum that is actually centred around free speech.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;These claims come one day after the Premier clearly stated his support for banning conversion therapy, so which is it?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is no room for conversion therapy in Tasmania. It is dangerous, not backed by science and causes serious harm to people involved. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This forum is not about free speech, it is about providing a space to spread misinformation and harmful beliefs not backed by science. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;That is why it is shocking to hear that Jeremy Rockliff supports backbencher Lara Alexander hosting this controversial forum. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is clear the Liberal Party is divided on this issue. Given the harm conversion therapy causes to vulnerable Tasmanians and the support it has from this controversial Government backbenchers, it is time for Jeremy Rockliff to show leadership and pull into line his MP.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ella Haddad MP&lt;br&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;Shadow Attorney General &lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Tasmanian Labor</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://taslabor.com/conversion-therapy-chaos-in-liberal-camp/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 05:40:28 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Paramedics’ industrial action a last resort</title><link>https://taslabor.com/paramedics-industrial-action-a-last-resort/</link><description>&lt;div class="content-body"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The Liberal government’s failure to address increasingly untenable working conditions has pushed Tasmania’s paramedics into taking unprecedented industrial action.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Paramedics will not attend Priority 3, Priority 4 or Low Priority jobs between 1 pm and 4 pm today – something they have never done before and a decision that has not been taken lightly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Our dedicated paramedics are taking this unprecedented action because they are under unprecedented pressure.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Workloads are unbearable, overtime is the norm, ramping is out of control and ambulance response times have blown out since the Liberals came to office.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Yet, the Liberals’ “final offer” to over-worked, under-resourced and under-paid workers ignores the solutions paramedics have put on the table.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As the government has been told over and over, today’s industrial action is not just about wages – it is also about addressing unsustainable working conditions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;These workplace pressures can no longer be ignored – the Premier owes it to our overworked and dedicated paramedics to listen to their concerns and prioritise taking the action needed to provide a safe and sustainable workplace.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Anita Dow MP&lt;br&gt;Shadow Health Minister&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Tasmanian Labor</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://taslabor.com/paramedics-industrial-action-a-last-resort/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 02:02:36 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government caps off horror week with another broken promise</title><link>https://taslabor.com/government-caps-off-horror-week-with-another-broken-promise/</link><description>&lt;div class="content-body"&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The Liberal Government has broken yet another promise. This week in the upper house the Liberal Government refused to disclose their failure to implement their land tax reform.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Their claims that land tax bills would go down under their leadership by $800 has now been called out as fantasy. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Land tax is now rising dramatically across the state, hurting small businesses, community organisations and households.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Earlier this week they were forced to admit they planned to spend $125 million subsidising rugby league and A-League matches in Hobart.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;They have gone head to head with Tasmania’s teachers, paramedics, firefighters, and child safety officers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The cost of their broken promise on energy is having a huge impact on businesses around the state, many of whom are seeing their contracted energy prices rise by 50 per cent.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;And now the Government has been caught out trying to cover up another broken promise on lower taxes.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Promised land tax bills would go down by $800, yet they have sharply risen all around the state. Affectively putting even more pressure on small businesses, community organisations and households who are already struggling with the soaring cost of living.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The treasurer needs to come clean and own up to this latest broken promise to embattled Tasmanians.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dean Winter MP   &lt;br&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Shadow Minister for Finance&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Shadow Minister for Economic Development&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Tasmanian Labor</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://taslabor.com/government-caps-off-horror-week-with-another-broken-promise/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 05:45:08 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Liberals’ contempt for teachers on full display</title><link>https://taslabor.com/liberals-contempt-for-teachers-on-full-display/</link><description>&lt;div class="content-body"&gt;
	        &lt;h2&gt;Liberals’ contempt for teachers on full display&lt;/h2&gt;
	        &lt;time&gt;Published November 9, 2022&lt;/time&gt;
	        
&lt;p&gt;The
Liberal government has demonstrated its contempt for Tasmania’s teachers with
its woeful display in Parliament this morning.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rather
than take responsibility for school closures, Premier Jeremy Rockliff and his
Education Minister Roger Jaensch both blamed teachers for today’s industrial
action, with Mr Rockliff labelling them “irresponsible” and Mr Jaensch saying
school closures are the fault of teachers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Schools
will be closed from lunch time – not because of teachers but because they are
fed up with being ignored.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As
the Premier has been told repeatedly, today’s industrial action is not just
about wages – it is also about addressing unsustainable working conditions.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our
teachers are the lowest paid in the country, they are working with less support
at a time when challenging student behaviours are on the rise, and stress leave
claims are up 54 per cent in the past three years.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For
the Premier to claim he values teachers and in the next breath call them
irresponsible is a huge insult when he is the one who has broken his promise to
work with and support them.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And
the Education Minister’s comments are just as appalling – especially coming on
top of his misleading claims that exams would be impacted and that teachers’
cries for more support were “nothing but posturing for the sake of it”.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tasmania’s teachers deserve our respect and support, not the contempt this government has shown them – and it is time the Premier showed some leadership, pulled his ministers into line and reached a fair pay deal with Tasmania’s essential workers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Rebecca White MP&lt;br&gt;Labor Leader&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Tasmanian Labor</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://taslabor.com/liberals-contempt-for-teachers-on-full-display/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:47:18 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>