<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Government of Western Australia</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au</link><description>Media statements from the Government of Western Australia</description><language>en-AU</language><copyright>Copyright State Government of Western Australia</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 13:01:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>Scrapy 2.4.1</generator><item><title>Supplier Wage Audit established to combat wage theft</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Supplier-Wage-Audit-established-to-combat-wage-theft.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Specialist employment conditions audit and compliance unit established&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;WA Government committed to ensuring suppliers to government comply with employment laws for their employees&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Government procurement processes strengthened with the inclusion of clauses for auditing employment and industrial relations practices&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Supplier Wage Audit branch has been established at the Department of Mines, Industry Regulation and Safety to monitor and audit the compliance of government suppliers and ensure they meet their employment obligations. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The branch will focus on contracts for services, subject to the Procurement Act 2020, that target high-risk industries such as cleaning and security. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Clauses have been added to goods, services and community services procurement templates to enable auditing and permit referrals in instances of non-compliance to the appropriate regulating authority. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guidance is available on the Department of Finance website at &lt;a href="https://www.wa.gov.au/government/publications/supplier-wage-audit-model-clause" target="_blank" title="Supplier Wage Audit Model Clause"&gt;https://www.wa.gov.au/government/publications/supplier-wage-audit-model-clause&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information, visit &lt;a href="http://www.dmirs.wa.gov.au/supplier-wage-audit" target="_blank" title="Supplier wage audit"&gt;http://www.dmirs.wa.gov.au/supplier-wage-audit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Industrial Relations Minister Bill Johnston:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The McGowan Government is committed to ensuring suppliers to government meet their industrial relations obligations. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This represents another step towards combating wage theft and is an important part of this Government's overall public sector reform election commitments."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Finance Minister Tony Buti:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Strengthening goods, services, community services and works procurement with these clauses is an important strategy for combating wage theft, particularly in high-risk industries. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The changes to whole of government procurement templates help to ensure that government suppliers comply with employment and industrial relations obligations for their employees."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Industrial Relations Minister's office - 6552 6700&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finance Minister's office - 6552 6400&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Bill Johnston MLA &amp; Hon Dr Tony Buti BPE DipEd MIR LLB DPhil MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Supplier-Wage-Audit-established-to-combat-wage-theft.aspx</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 16:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Useful upgrade supports growth of Gascoyne SES unit</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Useful-upgrade-supports-growth-of-Gascoyne-SES-unit.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Useless Loop State Emergency Service (SES) moves into new headquarters &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Facility houses the combined assets of Useless Loop SES and the Shark Bay Resources Emergency Response Team&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;A Gascoyne State Emergency Service (SES) unit now has a new and improved headquarters following a $140,000 upgrade that will bolster its operational and training capabilities. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Useless Loop SES officially moved into its new facility today following a handover ceremony with Emergency Services Minister Stephen Dawson and Fire and Emergency Services Commissioner Darren Klemm AFSM. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The SES unit will share its headquarters with the Shark Bay Resources Emergency Response Team under an agreement with the Department of Fire and Emergency Services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Shark Bay Resources contributed $90,000 to the upgrade, with the remaining $50,000 funded through the Emergency Services Levy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;In a boost to the wellbeing and development opportunities of volunteers, the upgraded facilities now feature: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;three offices; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;a larger training room; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;a kitchen; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;a laundry; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;a preparation area; and &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;storage spaces.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Formed in 1988 to service the mining town of the same name, Useless Loop SES &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;primarily attends road crashes, severe storms, rescues, and land searches around the southern peninsula of the Shire of Shark Bay, but also responds to major incidents in the Mid-West and Gascoyne. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The new facility is expected to help improve emergency response times in the remote area. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Emergency Services Minister Stephen Dawson:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"A key part of supporting WA's emergency services is to ensure our volunteers have access to modern facilities, enabling them to prepare and conduct their operations in the best possible environment. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"We can't take for granted the people who are prepared to drop everything at a moment's notice and put their lives on the line to protect their local community. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"These much-needed upgrades will not only make a big difference in how the Useless Loop SES train and respond to incidents, but also to build camaraderie within their own team and other emergency responders. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"This upgrade has been achieved through a successful partnership with the local community and businesses - and the Emergency Services Levy - to deliver a new collocated facility to support local volunteer response teams."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Mining and Pastoral Region MLC Peter Foster:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The Shire of Shark Bay is a busy area for travellers and tourists alike who rely on the skills and experience of our emergency services volunteers to keep them safe." &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"This upgraded collocated facility is most welcome and enables our local volunteers to prepare and provide an even greater service to support their local community."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister's office - 6552 5800&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Stephen Dawson MLC</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Useful-upgrade-supports-growth-of-Gascoyne-SES-unit.aspx</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Have a Go Day gets better with age</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Have-a-Go-Day-gets-better-with-age.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Free festival an opportunity for Seniors to try something new&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hula dancing, seated volleyball, rock climbing and canoeing among the activities on offer &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;2022 marks 30 years of Have a Go Day at Burswood Park &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seniors and Ageing Minister Don Punch has officially opened Have a Go Day for 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Organised by the Seniors Recreation Council with support from the McGowan Government, Have a Go Day is always a highlight of the Seniors Week calendar. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each year around 15,000 people attend the event at Burswood Park, which has been described as 'the Royal Show for Seniors'. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year there will be more than 200 information and activity sites, including 'hot hula' fitness classes, dance performances, games of walking football and seated volleyball, cooking demonstrations and language lessons.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are also dozens of booths offering information on health, lifestyle and technology. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The event is designed to remind Seniors of the importance of exercise, staying social, and keeping both physically and mentally activity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Have a Go Day started in 1991 at Taylor Reserve in South Perth, moved to McCallum Park the following year and then to Burswood Park where it's been held for the past 30 years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Seniors and Ageing Minister Don Punch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Have a Go Day is a fantastic opportunity to be active and engaged in the community - regardless of your age. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I thoroughly enjoyed attending my first Have a Go Day last year. Seeing the huge variety of activities on offer and meeting the Seniors taking part were real highlights.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"As Minister for Seniors and Ageing, I'm committed to raising the profile of older Western Australians and Have a Go Day is a great example of that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I congratulate the Seniors Recreation Council of WA on this great event and also give a big 'shout out' to the many volunteers who make the day possible."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister's office - 6552 6900&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Don Punch BPsych BSocwk MBA MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Have-a-Go-Day-gets-better-with-age.aspx</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 10:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New local government regulations gazetted for Council meetings to continue electronically</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/New-local-government-regulations-gazetted-for-Council-meetings-to-continue-electronically.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;New local government provisions for council meetings to be held electronically &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Part of McGowan Labor Government's sweeping local government reform agenda &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Local Government Minister John Carey has today introduced new provisions to enable Western Australian local governments to continue to conduct council meetings electronically.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new provisions, in effect from Wednesday, 9 November will:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;enable councils to hold up to half of all council meetings by electronic means; and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;provide for council members to, with the approval of the Mayor, Shire President, or majority of the council, attend a council meeting by electronic means. There will be a cap in the number of council meetings that a councillor can attend by electronic means, which will not apply to councillors living with a disability (as defined in the Disability Services Act 1993). &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Temporary provisions to enable councils to hold meetings electronically, and to enable councillors to attend via electronic means, were introduced in 2020 as part of the McGowan Government's immediate and world-leading response to the COVID-19 pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While these provisions have been introduced, and provide flexibility to the sector, local governments should make every effort to hold their meetings in person. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new regulations will be reviewed after a 12-month period. There will be a public consultation process, and members of the public will have the opportunity to provide feedback on how council meetings have operated under these regulations. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New provisions relating to livestreaming and recording of council meetings are also being progressed as part of the McGowan Government's local government reforms.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Local Government Minister John Carey:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"As part of our Government's sweeping package of local government reforms, changes to the regulations for council meetings have now been implemented.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"While the new provisions have been introduced to provide flexibility, it is important councils make every effort to continue to meet in person. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I understand for some local governments, particularly those in regional areas, electronic access can support councillors who live some distance away to participate in council decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I'm deeply proud of the McGowan Government's world-leading response in the face of the COVID-19 pandemic, as we acted swiftly not only to protect the health and wellbeing of WA, but also to ensure continuity of local governments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"A review of the provisions will be held after 12 months and will involve a public consultation period to provide feedback on how council meetings have operated under the new regulations. I'm looking forward to hearing feedback on these new measures."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister's office - 6552 5300&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon John Carey BA MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/New-local-government-regulations-gazetted-for-Council-meetings-to-continue-electronically.aspx</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 08:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Film and TV studio a step closer for Malaga METRONET station precinct</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Film-and-TV-studio-a-step-closer-for-Malaga-METRONET-station-precinct.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;McGowan Government identifies preferred location for screen production facility&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;New site offers prime access to future METRONET stations and Perth landmarks &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Economic diversification project to create jobs for creative industry when studio opens  &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Important step forward for major election commitment &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;First production at the facility to be welcomed in 2025&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Creative Industries Hub at E Shed in Fremantle being considered&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Western Australia's first dedicated screen production facility is a step closer - with detailed due diligence to commence on a 16-hectare site within the Malaga METRONET station precinct in Perth's north-east. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The proposed site - off Marshall Road and south of Whiteman Park - has been selected for its proximity to the Perth CBD and airport, access to future public transport, scale of the available land, and its direct access to major roads for travel to regional areas of the State.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The alternative site has been identified following several challenges with the original proposed location at Victoria Quay, Fremantle. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The screen production facility project was released by the State Government as a Problem and Opportunity Statement and is progressing through the Market-led Proposal process with Home Fire Pty Ltd as the preferred proponent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The State Government is continuing to negotiate with Home Fire on the commercial terms of development, with terms to be finalised in 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;As part of the ongoing negotiations, Home Fire will progress the proposal at the site, which includes site investigations, final design, and relevant planning applications. If the final proposal is approved by the State Government, it is anticipated that construction will commence in late 2023. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The negotiations will also consider a Creative Industries Hub at Victoria Quay's E Shed in Fremantle.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The development of a new screen production facility will support the McGowan Government's investment in the State's creative industries to diversify the economy through the attraction of film, TV, and screen projects to WA. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Home Fire's proposal is to design, construct, operate and maintain the studio. The proposed development will include purpose-built sound stages and other onsite screen production facilities such as production offices, an art department and wardrobe, workshops, a backlot, parking, and set storage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Consultation with the community on the proposed site will take place as part of any future planning applications.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Premier Mark McGowan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"Backing Western Australia's film and television industry is a critical part of our plan to diversify WA's economy and create new local job opportunities. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"Western Australia's natural beauty makes it an ideal location for film and TV production and having a world class screen production facility right here in Perth will make our State an even more attractive proposition for investment in interstate and international productions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"Today's announcement is another step forward on delivering our election commitment for a new screen production facility for Western Australia - supporting local industry and local jobs for our State."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Culture and the Arts Minister David Templeman: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"Western Australia is already home to an extremely talented creative sector, but it is recognised that a dedicated screen production facility is needed to put us in an even stronger position to attract larger and more complex national and international film and TV projects to our State. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"This announcement brings us closer to having the pivotal infrastructure needed to take our screen industry to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The studio has the potential to generate significant employment throughout its operations – that's including work and training for actors, camera operators, costume and set designers, sound and lighting technicians, video editors, and makeup artists. There will also be indirect benefits from attracting more film and TV shows to the State, including for accommodation providers, hospitality, and transport.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The McGowan Government's investment towards the screen production facility, alongside our commitment to the WA production attraction incentive program, is central to the State Government's Screen Industry Strategy. This strategy will help to grow this sector and create a highly skilled workforce to take advantage."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Planning Minister Rita Saffioti:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"As we deliver the METRONET Morley-Ellenbrook Line there is going to be significant scope for growth of new industries, and the delivery of a screen production facility within the new Malaga Station precinct is a fantastic example of the opportunities we have.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The future precinct will become a strategic community and employment hub for Perth's growing north-east - with a high-frequency train station, new homes and businesses, and now the potential for a one-of-a-kind screen production facility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"Home Fire will now undertake further due diligence on the site, including consultation with the City of Swan, Traditional Owners, and other relevant stakeholders - with opportunities for further feedback through any future development application process. Consultation with the City of Fremantle will also occur in relation to Home Fire's proposed creative industries hub.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The McGowan Government will continue to work closely with Home Fire on this proposal." &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Premier's Office: 6552 5000&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Culture and the Arts Minister's Office: 6552 5400&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Planning Minister's Office: 6552 5500&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Mark McGowan BA LLB MLA &amp; Hon David Templeman Dip Tchg BEd MLA &amp; Hon Rita Saffioti BBus MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Film-and-TV-studio-a-step-closer-for-Malaga-METRONET-station-precinct.aspx</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Government announces changes to Market-led Proposal policy</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Government-announces-changes-to-Market-led-Proposal-policy.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Government makes changes to Market-led Proposal policy to improve process&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Policy change will improve efficiency and transparency of process &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Industry feedback taken on, while providing better outcomes for all Western Australians&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The McGowan Government has today announced changes to its Market-led Proposals (MLP) policy that are aimed at improving the process, including better efficiency and transparency. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The MLP policy has been in operation since April 2019 and has received more than 70 proposals to date, with two progressing to the point of being implemented while one Problem and Opportunity statement has also been implemented.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The Market-led Proposals policy was set up as a pathway for the private sector to bring forward ideas and work with government to create jobs and stimulate the economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;MLPs allow the State Government to harness good ideas, private sector investment and entrepreneurship to develop projects that benefit Western Australians.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The review of the Market-led Proposal policy by the State Government investigated potential solutions to improve the timeframes, accountability and expectations of the policy and each lead agency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The changes to be implemented include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;reducing duplication so the MLP process includes only two stages rather than the current three;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;utilising a 'fast fail' mechanism that allows the Government to quickly decline proposals that are not aligned with Government priorities, or are unsuitable for the MLP process;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;introduction of target timeframes for both stages of the MLP process (under the previous policy, timeframes were only set for the first stage); &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;improved transparency - with more detailed summaries to be released during and after an MLP process (while ensuring probity and commercial-in-confidence); and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;improvements to the current webpage, and content on current and past MLPs, to make it easier for the public to navigate and access information.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;A new provision has also been finalised that requires proponents to formally commit to the State Government's specific MLP Probity Framework. This will reaffirm the probity requirements that form part of the terms and conditions of the MLP policy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Current MLPs will be managed on a case-by-case basis to ensure no proponent is disadvantaged by the transition to the new policy settings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Planning Minister Rita Saffioti:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The McGowan Government introduced the MLP process in 2019, as a way of responding to proposals brought forward to Government, and to work with industry to create jobs and stimulate the economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The process helps provide a formal mechanism for private sector to bring proposals to Government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"We've been very open from the outset that we will continue to look at ways of improving the process, and these policy changes are aimed at delivering the best outcomes for the State.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"We will be cutting down on areas of duplication and putting in place more target time frames to ensure the process is as efficient as possible for all parties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"We will be publishing more detailed summaries during live MLPs and at their conclusion so the community understands the decision-making process, and also the costs and benefits of a proposal to the Government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"We have made some simple changes to the current webpage and content to make it easier for the community to find information about current and past MLPs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"We will continue to look at ways we can further enhance the process in the future."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Minister's office - 6552 5500&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Rita Saffioti BBus MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Government-announces-changes-to-Market-led-Proposal-policy.aspx</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Waterwise initiatives helping WA public schools save millions of litres of precious water</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Waterwise-initiatives-helping-WA-public-schools-save-millions-of-litres-of-precious-water.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;New cross-government program to help public schools save groundwater &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nearly half a billion litres of drinking water already being saved through waterwise upgrades&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Individual schools to reduce drinking water consumption by around 11 per cent a year  &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;WA public schools use about 4.5 billion litres of scheme water annually&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Water Minister Dave Kelly today announced a new cross-government partnership and program designed to help State schools save precious groundwater. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Development of the new Waterwise School Grounds program will be informed by the outcomes of a water efficiency program that has been run in Western Australian public schools over the past two years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Since October 2020, 65 public schools - including 56 in regional WA - have benefited from waterwise upgrades under the Water Efficient Public Schools Program, delivered by Water Corporation and the Department of Education. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;On average, schools that participated in the initial two-year program are expected to use around 11 per cent less water through services such as plumbing retrofits, irrigation improvements, and rainwater harvesting. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The $1.5 million Water Efficient Public Schools Program aims to save around half a billion litres of drinking water over coming years - equivalent to 200 Olympic-sized swimming pools.    &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;WA public schools use about 4.5 billion litres of scheme water annually - some of which goes towards irrigating ovals and sporting grounds. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Findings from the initial program will help inform a new initiative between the Department of Education and Department of Water and Environmental Regulation aimed at saving even more of Perth's precious groundwater resources. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Known as the Waterwise School Grounds Program, it will see water audits and irrigation checks at metropolitan schools that use groundwater bores to irrigate ovals and playing fields. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Inefficient irrigation systems will be upgraded and school groundskeepers will receive waterwise training to help reduce on-campus water wastage.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The Waterwise School Grounds Program is one of several initiatives supporting water efficient schools within Kep Katitjin - Gabi Kaadadjan, the second Waterwise Perth Action Plan for Perth and Peel announced earlier this month. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Other actions under the plan include work by the Department of Education to incorporate waterwise design principles into buildings, landscaping, and grassed sporting spaces of new public primary and secondary schools. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Water Corporation will also aim to take the waterwise message to 50,000 WA students each year by 2030 by expanding its long-running and successful Waterwise Schools Program. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Since its inception in 2007, more than 330,000 students have taken part in the program, learning about the water cycle, how climate impacts our water sources, and the importance of water in Aboriginal culture.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Water Minister Dave Kelly: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We all have a role to play in protecting our State's water resources, which is why it's fantastic to see WA public schools taking such a proactive approach to water efficiency. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"When you consider State schools use around 4.5 billion litres of water each year, there is real opportunity to help reduce their usage and drive meaningful long-term savings.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We're already seeing the benefits of the Water Efficient Public Schools Program and, over time, the work completed at 65 campuses will help save nearly half a billion litres of water. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Lessons learnt will now be applied to the Waterwise School Grounds Program, which is another way the McGowan Government is acting to protect Perth's vital groundwater resources from the impacts of climate change." &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Education and Training Minister Sue Ellery: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"It's encouraging to see government agencies joining together to drive better waterwise outcomes for our schools and communities.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"In WA, perhaps more than anywhere else in the world, we understand and heed the waterwise message. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"A big part of that is thanks to the waterwise education delivered by Water Corporation to tens of thousands of WA students each year. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"I look forward to seeing programs within the Waterwise Perth Action Plan come to life, and to our public schools doing their part to help ensure a secure sustainable water supply long into the future." &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Water Minister's office - 6552 6100&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Education and Training Minister's office - 6552 5700&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Dave Kelly BA MLA &amp; Hon Sue Ellery BA MLC</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Waterwise-initiatives-helping-WA-public-schools-save-millions-of-litres-of-precious-water.aspx</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 10:35:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Final phase of Aboriginal cultural heritage co-design underway</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Final-phase-of-Aboriginal-cultural-heritage-co-design-underway.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Co-design process continues to support new Aboriginal cultural heritage laws&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Key documents released following second round of feedback&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More than 30 workshops to be held around the State&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The third and final phase of co-design to support implementation of the Aboriginal Cultural Heritage Act 2021 is underway, with the release of proposed guidelines to be discussed at more than 30 workshops across metropolitan, regional and remote communities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aboriginal Affairs Minister Tony Buti said that the workshops, commencing 14 November, provide a third and final opportunity for Aboriginal organisations, industry representatives and local communities to contribute to the design of key regulations and guidelines that will underpin the new Act.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These documents will guide land users and proponents through the new system to protect Aboriginal cultural heritage when the new laws come into effect from mid-2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Matters to be finalised include the proposed Aboriginal Cultural Heritage Management Code which details the required due diligence assessment, proposed activity and consultation guidelines that set the standard for engaging Aboriginal people about their cultural heritage. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Setting tiers of ground disturbance activities that could cause harm to Aboriginal cultural heritage will be another key discussion, to determine whether an approval would be required, and whether that should be a permit or a more comprehensive management plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Act provides for the establishment of local service providers giving Aboriginal people a statutory role in managing and protecting their local Aboriginal cultural heritage and putting them at the forefront of decision making. Fee guidelines for these Local Aboriginal Cultural Heritage Service (LACHS) will also be discussed at the workshops. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The co-design period ends on Friday, 6 January 2023. For more information, including about the LACHS funding, visit &lt;a href="https://wa.gov.au/ach-act" target="_blank" title="Aboriginal Cultural Heritage Act 2021 co-design process"&gt;https://wa.gov.au/ach-act&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Aboriginal Affairs Minister Tony Buti:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This third and final phase of co-design provides another opportunity for collaboration with Aboriginal people and organisations across the State to ensure we develop clear guidance for Traditional Owners, land users and the community. This is important as we edge closer to transition to the new Act. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I encourage anyone with an interest in Aboriginal cultural heritage, or who undertakes any form of civil or construction works or any form of land management activities, to read the documents and participate in one of our 34 workshops across the State.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Similarly, I encourage any Aboriginal organisation with an interest in becoming a LACHS to find out more about the LACHS readiness grants program. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The introduction of LACHS will provide certainty around the right people to consult, which will increase efficiencies in the heritage approvals process."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister's office - 6552 6400&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Dr Tony Buti BPE DipEd MIR LLB DPhil MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Final-phase-of-Aboriginal-cultural-heritage-co-design-underway.aspx</guid><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 12:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>National Rugby League Double-Header for Perth next year</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/National-Rugby-League-Double-Header-for-Perth-next-year.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Two back-to-back NRL matches to be played in Perth next year&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Single day spectacle to be played at award-winning Optus Stadium&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Weekend of sport to drive interstate visitation and boost economy &lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Western Australia will host two National Rugby League (NRL) matches in a one-day sporting spectacular next year as part of the NRL's 2023 calendar of events.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Perth's NRL Double Header will kick off on 5 August 2023, with both games to be played back-to-back at the award-winning Optus Stadium. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As part of their inaugural season, Queensland's Dolphins will take on the Newcastle Knights before the South Sydney Rabbitohs face the Cronulla-Sutherland Sharks in the same day. Fans will buy one ticket to watch both games.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NRL special event is supported by the WA Government, through Tourism WA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Double Header is expected to drive thousands of interstate visitors to WA, with travellers to inject millions into the State's economy through spending in hospitality and tourism businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next year's matches continue WA's strong relationship with the NRL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This year the sold out 2022 State of Origin match between the NSW Blues and Queensland Maroons saw nearly 7,000 out-of-state visitors travel to WA for the match, injecting more than $13.3 million into the economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The McGowan Government recently formed a cross-agency working group to investigate the development of a third-party bid for an 18th NRL team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For more information on the Double Header and 2023 NRL calendar visit &lt;a href="http://www.nrl.com/" target="_blank" title="National Rugby League website"&gt;nrl.com&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Tourism Minister Roger Cook:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"There is huge support for the NRL in Western Australia - and it keeps getting bigger every year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The atmosphere at the State of Origin this year was absolutely electric.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"What we are also seeing is east coast sports fans will travel to WA to watch matches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It's a fantastic boost for local tourism and hospitality businesses because the fans spend several days in WA enjoying themselves.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The WA Government is proud to support large-scale sporting contests to motivate visitors to travel to Western Australia and not only experience a world-class event, but then get out and explore our beautiful State."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Sport and Recreation Minister David Templeman:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This is going to be a fantastic double header for NRL fans in WA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The McGowan Government is committed to developing the sport here in Western Australia and has thrown its support behind a third party bid for a State-based team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Events such as this will help further grow the game at the grass roots level, ensuring a healthy future for the code."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tourism Minister's office - 6552 6500&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sport and Recreation Minister's office - 6552 5400&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Roger Cook BA GradDipBus MBA MLA &amp; Hon David Templeman Dip Tchg BEd MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/National-Rugby-League-Double-Header-for-Perth-next-year.aspx</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New pipelines to support growth in City of Swan</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/New-pipelines-to-support-growth-in-City-of-Swan.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;$36.5 million investment in new water infrastructure to support residential growth in Perth's north-eastern suburbs &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;18-kilometre wastewater pipeline, pump station and 2.6-kilometre water pipeline to be delivered by Water Corporation&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;McGowan Government has committed to invest $358 million in metropolitan water and wastewater projects this financial year&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The McGowan Government is investing $36.5 million in new water and wastewater infrastructure to cater for residential growth in the City of Swan under separate projects announced today by Water Minister Dave Kelly. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Water Corporation will construct an 18km wastewater pipeline from Bullsbrook to Ellenbrook and a 2.6km water pipeline in Henley Brook, with completion expected in late 2023. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wastewater works will include a new transfer pump station to safely divert flows from Bullsbrook Wastewater Treatment Plant to Beenyup Water Resource Recovery Facility, allowing the Bullsbrook plant to be decommissioned.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A new water pipeline along Starflower Road and Park Street will help transport drinking water to thousands of new and existing households in the fast-growing suburbs of Henley Brook, Ellenbrook and Brabham.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many properties within the City of Swan are semi-rural, however, population growth in the last decade has seen a significant increase in new residential developments in Perth's north-east.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Population in the City of Swan is expected to nearly double to 310,000 residents by 2051. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The McGowan Government has allocated $358 million to new metropolitan water projects this financial year. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Water Minister Dave Kelly:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This project is another example of the McGowan Government's commitment to provide the infrastructure and services our city needs to grow.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"As the population in Perth and Peel continues to increase our need for essential services does too, which is why we've committed $358 million towards new water projects for the metropolitan area this financial year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Swan Hills MLA Jessica Shaw:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It's important that infrastructure keeps pace with residential development particularly when it comes to vital services such as water and wastewater.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I welcome this further investment into the growing suburbs of Bullsbrook and Ellenbrook, and I commend the Water Corporation and its contractors for this local job."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to West Swan MLA Rita Saffioti:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The north-east of our city continues to grow rapidly, and with major investment in projects like the METRONET Morley-Ellenbrook train line, we will only see more people choosing to call this part of Perth home.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"As our community grows, it's essential we deliver the necessary infrastructure to support residential expansion, which is why investment in these new water and wastewater facilities is so important."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister's office - 6552 6100&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Dave Kelly BA MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/New-pipelines-to-support-growth-in-City-of-Swan.aspx</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 10:10:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Bunbury wheelchair access on the right track</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Bunbury-wheelchair-access-on-the-right-track.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;New Freedom Trax device in place at Dolphin Discovery Centre&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Better access to beaches and attractions around Bunbury &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More opportunities for people with disability to participate in recreation activities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;People with disability will be able to enjoy more of Bunbury thanks to a new motorised, all-terrain wheelchair attachment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The Freedom Trax attaches to a manual wheelchair and was purchased by the City of Bunbury with a $10,000 State Government grant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;As its name suggests, the Freedom Trax uses tank-like tracks instead of wheels to glide over obstacles and traverse uneven terrain, including sand, dirt tracks, grass, wood chips and gravel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The Freedom Trax will allow people with disability to move independently and access Koombana Bay, Back Beach, the Leschenault Inlet, Mangrove Cove, Maidens Park and Manea Park, as well as surrounding trails, parks and beaches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The device will be stored at the Dolphin Discovery Centre at Koombana Bay which is open seven days a week. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The City of Bunbury will set up a booking system for the Freedom Trax and staff at the Dolphin Discovery Centre will help users fit the device to their wheelchair.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;A dozen organisations shared in $100,000, as part of a McGowan Government election commitment to increase the number of all-terrain wheelchairs in WA. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Disability Services Minister Don Punch:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"Making sure everyone has access to the outdoors and the activities that go with it is key to creating an inclusive community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The Freedom Trax will allow people with disability to access Bunbury's world class beaches and attractions. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"Everyone deserves the opportunity to enjoy this beautiful area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The all-terrain wheelchair grants program has proven to be very popular with local governments, surf life saving clubs and community organisations, making National Parks and beaches across WA more accessible, inclusive and welcoming for people with disability.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"Improving the availability of devices like the Freedom Trax and all-terrain wheelchairs will support people with disability to connect to their community and increase participation in recreation activities in the natural environment."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Minister's office - 6552 6900&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Don Punch BPsych BSocwk MBA MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Bunbury-wheelchair-access-on-the-right-track.aspx</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WA's joint force approach to defence industry collaboration</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/WAs-joint-force-approach-to-defence-industry-collaboration.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;McGowan Government launches Western Australian Defence Industry Workforce Development Plan 2022-27&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Plan sets out a united approach to skilling WA's defence industry workforce&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Driving collaboration across schools, TAFEs, specialist training providers, Western Australian universities, and unions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Building on the State Government's work to diversify WA's economy&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The McGowan Government has unveiled its blueprint to build a strong and sustainable local defence industry, including analysis, planning, and investment to support the sector's workforce and diversify Western Australia's economy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Western Australian Defence Industry Workforce Development Plan 2022−27 is a 'WA joint force' approach to building defence capabilities across all five defence domains.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The plan has been developed through the Department of Training and Workforce Development's Western Australian Defence Industry Workforce Office and co-signatories comprised of government agencies, Team WA universities, TAFE, and unions working with the State's defence industry and peak representative bodies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A key focus of the plan is boosting WA's capability to develop a pipeline of skilled professional and para-professional defence industry workers, including university graduates and skilled trade workers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It will guide the State Government's work with the Commonwealth Government, industry, and education and training sectors to further strengthen the State's defence industry skills and capabilities to:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;give WA a competitive advantage;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;grow its 'smart' industry 4.0 skill capabilities;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;engage with individuals, veterans, businesses, and the wider public to improve access to information, defence industry careers, and job opportunities; and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;provide the skills needed for the current and future defence industry workforce.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The strategic initiatives in the plan will be delivered to meet the needs of key WA defence industry stakeholders while supporting national defence interests.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The McGowan Government has already invested $35 million to directly support the development of a strong and sustainable sovereign defence industry workforce.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This includes $11 million in the 2022-23 State Budget to further build the WA defence industry's professional and para-professional workforce by supporting internship and graduate scholarships, industry grants to upskill and reskill workers, and improved articulation of courses between WA universities and TAFE.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.04px;"&gt;To view the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;em style="font-size:14.04px;"&gt;WA Defence Industry Workforce Development Plan 2022–27&lt;/em&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.04px;"&gt;, please visit &lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.jobsandskills.wa.gov.au/defence#defence-industry-workforce-development-plan" target="_blank" title="Western Australian Defence Industry Workforce Development Plan 2022-27" style="font-size:14.04px;"&gt;jobsandskills.wa.gov.au/defence#defence-industry-workforce-development-plan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.04px;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Premier Mark McGowan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Western Australia's world-leading defence industry increasingly has a vital role in the State's economy and economic diversification.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Through the Western Australian Defence Industry Workforce Development Plan 2022−27, my Government is taking its already significant work to support and grow our defence industry workforce to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"WA's united team approach of government, industry, and tertiary sectors working together will ensure our State continues to be a strong contender for defence projects as we continue to build the skilled and diverse workforce needed to deliver them."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Education and Training Minister Sue Ellery:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Attracting future defence work requires a workforce recognised as one of the most highly educated, qualified, and skilled of its type in the world.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Western Australia's education and training system is ready to meet this challenge as evidenced by the valuable contribution of the WA universities and TAFE to the development and implementation of this plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Thanks to the commitment and shared vision of this plan's co-signatories, we have a solid roadmap for collaboration, and to drive our investment in the skilled defence industry workforce further."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Defence Industry Minister Paul Papalia:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The McGowan Government is committed to growing WA's defence industry and ensuring the State harnesses its competitive advantages.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"As the competition for skills is increasing across the nation, this plan outlines strategies to address forecast demand in the key defence industry occupations for WA over the coming decade.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Our growing defence industry workforce is bringing a whole range of diverse, rewarding, and long-term career opportunities, including in skilled professional and para-professional roles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This plan will help WA prepare for its pivotal role as the future home of our nation's nuclear submarines, and the sustainment hub for our AUKUS allies. We are creating the skills and capabilities of the future, today."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Premier's office - 6552 5000&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Education and Training Minister's office - 6552 5700&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Defence Industry Minister's office - 6552 5600&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Mark McGowan BA LLB MLA &amp; Hon Sue Ellery BA MLC &amp; Hon Paul Papalia CSC MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/WAs-joint-force-approach-to-defence-industry-collaboration.aspx</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 09:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Position statement on improving development of childcare centres</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Position-statement-on-improving-development-of-childcare-centres.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Draft position statement to deliver better planning outcomes for childcare premises&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Provides location and design guidance to decision-makers, proponents, and the community&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Feedback will help finalise a consistent planning policy approach&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;A draft position statement to guide the development of childcare premises to better meet the community's changing needs is now open for public comment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Childcare is an essential community service, and with the rising demand in both metropolitan and regional areas it is important to ensure that the development of childcare premises occurs in appropriate locations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The draft Position Statement: Child Care Premises would update the existing Planning Bulletin 72 (2009) and will provide guidance to key planning decision makers - including local governments and joint development assessment panels - when preparing local scheme provisions and planning policies for childcare centres.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The draft addresses a number of important planning considerations, including: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;location; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;site characteristics; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;environmental suitability; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;design; &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;traffic and vehicle access;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;noise emissions;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;amenity; and &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;health and safety impacts.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;It also supports delivery of the State Government's Educare election commitment, by encouraging the co-location of childcare with schools. This allows for the development of childcare premises to be considered when planning new public primary schools, providing communities with certainty about the future of childcare services in their area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The draft proposes that childcare premises could also be co-located on government reserves - such as hospitals - as well as within mixed commercial zones - such as shopping centres - or on office or commercial zoned land. This allows for flexible hours of operation, catering to the increasing number of families who have irregular or out-of-ordinary work hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;To have your say, visit &lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;font-family:arial, sans-serif;color:#005078;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://consultation.dplh.wa.gov.au/land-use-planning/child-care/" target="_blank" title="Position Statement: Child Care Premises"&gt;https://consultation.dplh.wa.gov.au/land-use-planning/child-care/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Consultation closes at 5pm on Friday, 10 February 2023. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Planning Minister Rita Saffioti:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Western Australia is a rapidly evolving State, and it's absolutely essential our planning policies and guidelines keep pace with the expectations of the community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This draft position statement will provide key decision makers with updated guidance for planning childcare centres and responds to our changing community needs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The draft position statement outlines changes that would allow childcare premises to be co-located with new primary school sites - a key part of our Government's Educare election commitment - as well as in a wider variety of settings including around hospitals, shopping centres, and offices where they can operate varied hours. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I encourage the community to review the draft position statement and provide feedback about planning for future childcare premises."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Community Services Minister Simone McGurk:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Childcare is so important not only for children's socialisation and education, but also to support parents - especially women - to return to work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Childcare is a responsibility of all levels of government, and with services in high demand, we are committed to doing what we can at a State Government level to improve access and convenience for families.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Now is the time for the community to have their say on this important issue that will impact future childcare planning and development."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Planning Minister's office - 6552 5500&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.04px;"&gt;Community Services Minister's office - 6552 6600&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Rita Saffioti BBus MLA &amp; Hon Simone McGurk BA(Arts) BA(Comms) MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Position-statement-on-improving-development-of-childcare-centres.aspx</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Potential grows for the Avon Industrial Park</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Potential-grows-for-the-Avon-Industrial-Park.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;CBH Group has purchased a 105-hectare site at the Avon Industrial Park&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The investment is the most significant in the Park's history&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The Avon Industrial Park forms an integral part of Northam's broader freight and logistics precinct&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The McGowan Government welcomes the significant investment CBH Group (CBH) has made in the future of the Wheatbelt and the Western Australian grain supply chain with the purchase of a 105-hectare site at the Avon Industrial Park.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The proposed primary receival site, known as 'Meenaar', is a critical component in CBH's goal to increase monthly peak export capacity from 1.6 to 3 million tonnes by 2033. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The project is expected to generate up to 140 jobs at the peak of construction, with 40 ongoing jobs in operations and transport. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Managed by DevelopmentWA and overseen by the Avon Industrial Park Advisory Committee, a sub-committee of the Wheatbelt Development Commission, the Avon Industrial Park has experienced strong growth over the past 18 months.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;In October 2021, the State Government allocated $200,000 through the Regional Development Leverage Fund in partnership with CBH to undertake road and rail design and costing assessments to improve freight access and complement future expansion of the park.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;CBH's purchase is the single largest development in the park's history and is a significant economic development opportunity for Northam and the broader Avon Sub-region. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Located on the outskirts of Northam on both interstate rail and road networks, the 470-hectare Avon Industrial Park accommodates a number of businesses servicing the rural, resources and mineral processing industries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The Avon Industrial Park is part of a suite of strategic freight network assets near Northam, bolstering the town's position as a burgeoning intermodal freight hub on the doorstep of the Perth metropolitan area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Regional Development Minister Alannah MacTiernan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"This is a significant investment for the Wheatbelt and Northam that will greatly benefit both the regional economy and the Western Australian agricultural industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The investment and work underway to further activate and expand the park forms part of the State Government's broader commitment to diversify regional economies and enhance freight efficiencies to benefit WA businesses. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The State Government will continue to work with local government and industry to maximise these economic benefits."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Lands Minister John Carey:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Our Government is committed to utilising Government-owned land to deliver both economic and social outcomes that benefit the Western Australian community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Avon Industrial Park continues its strong growth and is boosting employment opportunities, while driving economic development right across the State.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Our Government welcomes CBH Group's and the Shire of Northam's commitment to the estate, reflecting Northam's significance as the economic hub of the Wheatbelt and its importance to the agricultural sector."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Regional Development Minister's office - 6552 6200&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Lands Minister's office - 6552 5300&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Alannah MacTiernan MLC &amp; Hon John Carey BA MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Potential-grows-for-the-Avon-Industrial-Park.aspx</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 13:05:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Extended retail trading hours to increase Christmas convenience</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Extended-retail-trading-hours-to-increase-Christmas-convenience.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Online shoppers urged to be vigilant as scammers expected to be active&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;An additional 37 trading hours approved to make Christmas and Australia Day shopping more convenient&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;57 extra hours of trading between Labour Day in March this year and Australia Day next year&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Western Australian shoppers are being urged by the State Government to be cyber safe this Christmas by being vigilant to scams while shopping online.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fake websites and social media advertising may set a trap for online shoppers looking for a bargain and could put them at risk of losing their money. In 2021, WA consumers lost almost $730,000 to online shopping scams.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Advice to consumers is to only shop on well-known and reliable websites and, if websites ask for direct bank transfer as the only payment method, be very suspicious. Paying by credit card or a secure payment method such as PayPal is safer, as there is greater chance of getting the money back if the gift is not delivered.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To be totally safe, the best option for Christmas shoppers is to buy from a local "bricks and mortar" store, where they can take immediate possession of the gift and not be impacted by potential delays in postage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make Christmas shopping at stores more convenient, 33 extra trading hours for general retail shops in the Perth metropolitan area have been approved and will begin on Saturday, 10 December 2022 ending on Monday, 2 January 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During this period, Sunday and public holiday trading has been extended an extra four hours a day, 8am to 6pm (normally 11am to 5pm), with an additional one hour on Saturdays, 8am to 6pm (normally 8am to 5pm).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;From Monday, 19 December 2021 until Christmas Eve inclusive, larger shops can choose to open one hour earlier from 7am until 9pm on weekdays (normally 8am to 9pm).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, trading for the Australia Day public holiday on Thursday, 26 January 2023 will also be extended by four hours, 8am to 6pm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This means an extra 57 hours of trading has been added since March Labour Day holidays this year and Australia Day next year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Commerce Minister Roger Cook:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Fake websites look very professional and may even steal the identity of a well-known retailer or brand, so it's easy to be fooled and consumers need to be alert. The items for sale may also be offered at very low prices which may lure people to try to bag a bargain.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"When consumers report fake websites to WA ScamNet at Consumer Protection, the team works with domains and network hosts to get them taken down. However, it will never be possible to close down all these fake websites and social media pages, so it's really important that online shoppers are cautious before entering their personal and financial information during a purchase, unless they are confident the site is genuine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"To encourage shopping at stores, we have extended retail trading hours this Christmas that will boost consumer convenience and hopefully stimulate sales to support the retail sector."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister's office - 6552 6500&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table cellspacing="0" class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:48%;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" style="width:38%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default" style="width:17%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday-Friday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" style="width:14%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default" style="width:13%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" style="width:22%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public holidays*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="ms-rteTableOddRow-default"&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" style="width:38%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Normal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default" style="width:17%;"&gt;8am-9pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" style="width:14%;"&gt;8am-5pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTableOddCol-default" style="width:13%;"&gt;11am-5pm&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" style="width:22%;"&gt;11am-5pm&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr class="ms-rteTableEvenRow-default"&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTableEvenCol-default" colspan="5" style="width:50%;"&gt;*Excludes Christmas Day, Good Friday and Anzac Day when general retail shops remain closed ​ ​ ​ ​&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table cellspacing="0" class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:48%;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday 10 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8am to 6pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;   &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday 11 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8am to 6pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;Monday 12 December 2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;8am to 9pm (Normal Trading)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;Tuesday 13 December 2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;8am to 9pm (Normal Trading)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;Wednesday 14 December 2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;8am to 9pm (Normal Trading)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;Thursday 15 December 2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;8am to 9pm (Normal Trading)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;Friday 16 December 2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;8am to 9pm (Normal Trading)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday 17 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8am to 6pm &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday 18 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8am to 6pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday 19 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7am to 9pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday 20 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7am to 9pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday 21 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7am to 9pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday 22 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7am to 9pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday 23 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7am to 9pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday 24 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8am to 6pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;Sunday 25 December 2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;Closed (Christmas Day)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday 26 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8am to 6pm (Boxing Day)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuesday 27 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8am to 6pm&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(Boxing Day public holiday)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;Wednesday 28 December 2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;8am to 9pm (Normal Trading)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;Thursday 29 December 2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;8am to 9pm (Normal Trading)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;Friday 30 December 2022&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;8am to 9pm (Normal Trading)&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Saturday 31 December 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8am to 6pm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunday 1 January 2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8am to 6pm (New Year's Day)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday 2 January 2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8am to 6pm (New Year's Day public holiday)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:50%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday 26 January 2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8am to 6pm (Australia Day public holiday)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Roger Cook BA GradDipBus MBA MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Extended-retail-trading-hours-to-increase-Christmas-convenience.aspx</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>WA Government delivers for veteran initiatives and support services</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/WA-Government-delivers-for-veteran-initiatives-and-support-services.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Twelve organisations to receive grants totalling almost $1.3 million through the 2022 ANZAC Day Trust Grants Program&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Program provides funding to ex-service organisations to support the welfare of veterans and their families&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;WA Government committed to assisting veterans transitioning back into civilian life&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The WA Government is delivering certainty to local organisations supporting veterans and their families, with almost $1.3 million in grants to be allocated through the 2022 ANZAC Day Trust Grants Program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Grants ranging from $300 to more than $380,000 will be shared by 12 organisations and used to fund a range of initiatives and support services.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Royal Australian Air Force Association of Western Australia will receive a $157,450 grant to help fund the development of the Andrew Russell Veteran Living Program, which will deliver accommodation and supporting services for WA veterans suffering homelessness. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the 2021-22 State Budget, the WA Government significantly increased the annual ANZAC Day Trust Grants Program to $1.3 million per year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This increase has given certainty to ex-service organisations working on the front line, such as Legacy WA and the Returned and Services League in WA (RSLWA), allowing them to look beyond single-year funding cycles.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four projects are receiving their second year of funding, including the Veterans Employment Program, a partnership between RSLWA and Working Spirit.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The program delivers employment services and has already exceeded the benchmarks set for 2022 in linking veterans and their families with employers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Legacy WA will use its $380,262 grant to continue three programs designed to assist hundreds of veterans and their families, widows and children who have lost a parent. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just over $283,000 will be shared across five organisations to assist with the construction of memorials or organisation of commemorative services. These projects will help to ensure Western Australians remember the sacrifices of previous generations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Veterans Issues Minister Paul Papalia:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We must never forget the sacrifice our service-men and women have made to maintain the freedom and prosperity we experience in Australia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"It has been just over a year since we announced a significant increase to the annual ANZAC Day Trust Grants Program and we are seeing the benefits of the WA Government delivering certainty for ex-service organisations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We are committed to supporting the veterans and their families that call WA home, and assisting with their transition back to civilian life."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister's office - 6552 5600&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table cellspacing="0" class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:58%;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;strong style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Organisation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:33.3333%;"&gt;&lt;strong style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Activity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:33.3333%;"&gt;&lt;strong style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$ Amount&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Allied Merchant Seamen's Association&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Banner&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$300&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Australian Army Training Team Vietnam (Western Australia Branch)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Commemoration and lunch&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$720&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Combined Defence Force Support Association of WA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Advocacy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$2,775&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Connected By Inc&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Connected By Mountain Biking&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$60,000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;HMAS Perth Memorial Foundation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;HMAS Perth Memorial construction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$167,000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Legacy WA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Operational support&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Second year funding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$380,262&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Our Veterans Forge&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Veterans blacksmithing&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$17,000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Royal Australian Air Force Association of WA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Andrew Russell Veteran Living Program &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$157,450&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Returned and Services League and Working Spirit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Veteran Employment Program&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Second year funding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$317,036&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Korean Prisoner's PWMA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Korean War Memorial construction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Second year funding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$40,000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Battle of Crete Memorial Committee WA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Battle of Crete Memorial construction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Second year funding&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$75,000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Veterans Transition Centre&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Operational support&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$80,000&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Paul Papalia CSC MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/WA-Government-delivers-for-veteran-initiatives-and-support-services.aspx</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 09:20:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Cutting-edge machines to train WA defence industry workers</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Cutting-edge-machines-to-train-WA-defence-industry-workers.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Four state-of-the-art multi-axis computer numerical control machines to prepare job-ready workers for the defence industry&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;New TAFE equipment supporting defence training and delivery of low-fee skill sets&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;McGowan Government initiatives to expand WA's defence industry capabilities&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Students and the defence industry have received a major boost with the installation of new state-of-the-art machinery at South Metropolitan TAFE's Rockingham campus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Four new computer numerical control (CNC) milling and lathe machines have been unveiled which will enable students to train on the latest equipment used by the defence industry to manufacture parts with exceptional precision and efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The McGowan Government is successfully progressing its strategy to build a strong local defence industry workforce and support the sector's role in economic diversification and job creation in Western Australia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In line with the Western Australian Defence Industry Workforce Development Plan 2022-27 launched today by Premier Mark McGowan, Education and Training Minister Sue Ellery and Defence Industry Minister Paul Papalia, South Metropolitan TAFE students will use the modern CNC machines to gain hands-on experience in manufacturing components for key defence maritime trades.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The new machines were funded as part of an $18 million McGowan Government investment in growing the State's defence workforce capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They are being used to teach apprentices programming, setting and operation of the latest CNC equipment with multi-axis and ferrous and non-ferrous materials, and can also support training in making components for a range of other industries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Benefits of this game-changing technology for industry include its potential to produce larger quantities of parts with less manual labour while reducing risk of human error or injury. It can also reduce the time required to machine important parts (for example, a pump shaft for a vessel of any size or shape) by up to 50 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The investment also enables South Metropolitan TAFE, which was awarded Academic Institution of the Year at the Australian Defence Industry Awards in September, to deliver post-trade training in advanced CNC operations and programming above Certificate III level. This includes delivery of two of seven new low-fee Defence Ready Skill Sets that the State Government has made available to help make existing workers defence-ready.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The machines are programmed with Mastercam software to help address demand for CNC programmers and machine operators in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The State Government's investment also includes 16 new welding simulators for South Metropolitan TAFE's Naval Base campus.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Several defence-related qualifications have already had their course fees reduced by up to 72 per cent as part of the McGowan Government's highly successful Lower fees, local skills initiative.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Information on defence industry training opportunities is available on the Jobs and Skills WA website at &lt;a href="http://www.jobsandskills.wa.gov.au/defence" target="_blank" title="Jobs and Skills WA - Defence"&gt;http://www.jobsandskills.wa.gov.au/defence&lt;/a&gt; or by contacting the dedicated Defence Industry Team at Rockingham Jobs and Skills Centre on (08) 9559 8655.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Premier Mark McGowan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"My Government continues to invest in training local people so they have the skills needed for defence and other priority industries.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"These new state-of-the-art CNC machines will support training in blue collar trades needed for the maritime defence industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Providing TAFEs with modern equipment for students to train on, and prepare for a seamless transition to the workforce, is crucial to support the reskilling and upskilling of veterans, existing defence workers and new entrants to the industry."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Education and Training Minister Sue Ellery:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"South Metropolitan TAFE was recognised as the nation's leading defence industry trainer earlier this year, and its specialist training programs and links with industry are ensuring Western Australians are being trained to industry standard to take up defence job opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Our strong investment in initiatives to boost WA's defence industry workforce has generated more than 430 new apprentices for the sector in the past two years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Strong defence industry training is crucial to get Western Australia ready for a rapid scale-up of defence and shipbuilding projects, and we are delivering a range of workforce initiatives to make this possible."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Defence Industry Minister Paul Papalia:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Western Australia is Australia's frontline for defence in the Indo-Pacific region and a key contributor to defence requirements nationally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Our defence industry is competitive, flexible and resilient and our advanced manufacturing capabilities and world-class tertiary institutions are contributing to its strength.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Key areas of focus for the McGowan Government are future-proofing the State's sovereign workforce and creating opportunities for veterans to transition into defence industry jobs with wraparound support and guidance."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Premier's office - 6552 5000&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Education and Training Minister's office - 6552 5700&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Defence Industry Minister's office - 6552 5600&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Mark McGowan BA LLB MLA &amp; Hon Sue Ellery BA MLC &amp; Hon Paul Papalia CSC MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Cutting-edge-machines-to-train-WA-defence-industry-workers.aspx</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Students to commemorate WWII history on Premier's ANZAC tour</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Students-to-commemorate-WWII-history-on-Premier's-ANZAC-tour.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Premier's ANZAC Student Tour participants announced for 2023&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Group of 10 students will commemorate the service of ANZAC men and women in Sydney and New Zealand&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Students from schools across Western Australia will share in memorable history lessons and commemorate the service of ANZAC men and women as part of the 2023 Premier's ANZAC Student Tour. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Premier Mark McGowan and Education and Training Minister Sue Ellery today announced that the students from 10 different schools have been selected to participate in the tour and will travel to Sydney and New Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Accompanied by three teachers, the group of students will depart for the 10-day tour on 16 April.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The unique 2023 program gives students an opportunity to investigate the ANZAC legacy and commemorate the men and women who served in the armed forces, and the 78th anniversary of the end of World War II.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The Premier's ANZAC Student Tour is an annual competition open for all WA students in Years 8 to 11. Since 2004, a total of 246 secondary students have taken part.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;This year's participants were selected based on their response to the question: 'In what way might efforts on the home front be seen as important as battles fought overseas?' &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The 2023 Premier's ANZAC Student Tour participants include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Year 8 Elizaveta Fedotova from Bob Hawke College;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Year 8 Adoley Mensah from Wyndham District High School;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Year 9 Poppy Fletcher from Mount Lawley Senior High School;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Year 9 Joshua Patrick from Northam Senior High School;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Year 10 Harry Forman from Katanning Senior High School;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Year 10 Georgia Kikiros from St Andrew's Grammar;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Year 10 Zoe Stockdale from Kalgoorlie-Boulder Community High School;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Year 10 Lila Wenzel from Albany Senior High School;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Year 11 Rishita Sarkar from Perth Modern School; and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Year 11 Ebony Whitney from Collie Senior High School.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;More information about the Premier's ANZAC Student Tour is available at &lt;a href="https://www.education.wa.edu.au/premiers-anzac-student-tour" target="_blank" title="Premier's ANZAC Student Tour"&gt;https://www.education.wa.edu.au/premiers-ANZAC-student-tour&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Education and Training Minister Sue Ellery:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The Premier's ANZAC Student Tour offers a unique opportunity for Western Australian students to commemorate and learn about the service of ANZAC men and women.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"Each year it's great to see that more WA students are interested in exploring Australia's military history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The 10 students participating in the 2023 tour will learn a lot from this experience, and be able to share the significant knowledge they gain with others at their school and in the wider community." &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Minister's office - 6552 5700&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Sue Ellery BA MLC</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Students-to-commemorate-WWII-history-on-Premier's-ANZAC-tour.aspx</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Consultation to inform education requirements for strata managers</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Consultation-to-inform-education-requirements-for-strata-managers.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Consultation paper proposes changes to educational requirements for strata managers&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Feedback to shape changes to the Strata Titles (General) Regulations 2019&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Submissions open from today until 2 December 2022&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Strata management industry representatives and stakeholders are encouraged to have their say on proposed changes to educational requirements for those working in Western Australia's strata management industry. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Released today by Landgate, the consultation paper was developed in collaboration with the Strata Community Association (WA), REIWA and the Property Council. It outlines a new proposed model for educational qualifications for the strata management industry. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In WA, the Strata Titles (General) Regulations 2019 (STR) outline the educational qualifications for strata management industry employees. This includes the Certificate IV in Strata Community Management.   &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Information gathered through the consultation process will be used to inform any future amendments to the STR.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Submissions close at 5pm AWST on 2 December 2022. To read the consultation paper or to provide feedback, visit the Landgate &lt;a href="https://www0.landgate.wa.gov.au/titles-and-surveys/strata-titles/Review-of-strata-manager-educational-qualification-requirements/" target="_blank" title="Review of strata manager educational qualification requirements"&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comments attributed to Lands Minister John Carey:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The strata management industry is an important economic contributor to the State, with almost 29,000 strata lots sold in the last financial year, with a value of just under $14 billion. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"This consultation paper will play an important role in ensuring educational requirements for people working in the strata management industry are clear, accessible, and appropriate. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I encourage the strata management industry and anyone with feedback to have their say as part of this consultation process to ensure Landgate can propose changes to WA's strata titles regulations that best meet the needs of those that live in or manage these schemes."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister's office - 6552 5300&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon John Carey BA MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Consultation-to-inform-education-requirements-for-strata-managers.aspx</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 10:15:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Education assistants, cleaners and gardeners accept wages offer</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Education-assistants,-cleaners-and-gardeners-accept-wages-offer.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Education assistants, cleaners and gardeners accept wages offer &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;$60 per week increase for eligible employees and up to $3,000 cost of living payment&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nearly 80,000 public sector workers have accepted State Government's wages offer&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;More than 16,000 education assistants, cleaners and gardeners - mainly employed by the Department of Education - have accepted the State Government's wages policy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over 98.7 per cent of United Workers Union members who voted were in support of the two agreements. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Employees covered by the agreements will receive a $60 per week increase from 1 January 2023. Department of Education will be administering one-off cost of living payments of up to $3,000 in the coming weeks, with employees to receive their payment before Christmas.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The replacement agreement for education assistants includes several new and improved conditions of employment, including:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;a new classification for employees providing support to special needs students in Education Support Centres and Education Support Schools; and &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;an allowance for employees with a NAATI recognised Auslan qualification, in acknowledgement of the educational outcomes it supports in delivering for students who are deaf or hard of hearing.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cleaners and gardeners have secured further enhancements to employment conditions and greater workplace flexibilities. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Agreement from these groups takes the total number of public sector employees who have accepted the State Government's public sector wages policy to over 79,000.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Industrial Relations Minister Bill Johnston:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"I'm pleased United Workers Union members have endorsed the offer and commend the union for their commitment to reaching this positive outcome. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The McGowan Government is pleased that public sector unions and the workforces they represent are accepting our revision to wages policy. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We look forward to securing more negotiated settlements before Christmas. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Under this policy, a Level 1 cleaner - whose annual salary is $52,490 - will receive the equivalent of an 11.68 per cent increase in the first year, inclusive of the one-off cost of living payment."  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister's office - 6552 6700&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Bill Johnston MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Education-assistants,-cleaners-and-gardeners-accept-wages-offer.aspx</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 12:40:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>New kitchen showcases Carnarvon’s premier produce</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/New-kitchen-showcases-Carnarvon%E2%80%99s-premier-produce.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Taste of Italy by Valeria officially opened in Carnarvon &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The new commercial kitchen was supported with a $100,000 Regional Economic Development (RED) Grant&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Minister for Regional Development Alannah MacTiernan visited Carnarvon today to officially open a new commercial kitchen showcasing the Gascoyne food bowl's premier local produce.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Taste of Italy by Valeria is a delicatessen and catering business that provides Italian-influenced cuisine, serving breakfast and lunch options to the Carnarvon community.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The project was supported by the McGowan Government through the $45.8 million Regional Economic Development (RED) Grants program, which aims to enhance economic development and job creation in regional Western Australia. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;More than 45 new Gascoyne-based jobs have been created through investment in local businesses and community initiatives since RED Grants commenced in 2018. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Regional Development Minister Alannah MacTiernan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"We have supported owner and operator Valeria Lucchitto to build her small business, providing $100,000 toward the project. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"Valeria's food and flavours showcase Carnarvon's amazing local produce and are helping to put the region on the culinary map. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"We want visitors to know that Carnarvon is a great place to stop and stay on their way North."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Minister's office - 6552 6200&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Alannah MacTiernan MLC</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/New-kitchen-showcases-Carnarvon%E2%80%99s-premier-produce.aspx</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 13:45:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Nearly $40 million funding to deliver more than 150 social housing dwellings</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Nearly-$40-million-funding-to-deliver-more-than-150-social-housing-dwellings.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;li&gt;Up to $39,561,549 in grants to be awarded for new social housing &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;More than 150 new social dwellings to be delivered under additional funding round&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Grants will support construction projects across five regions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Housing Minister John Carey has announced 12 community housing organisations and local governments will share in a further $39 million in funding to deliver more than 150 new social housing properties across Western Australia.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The grants are provided through the McGowan Government's Social Housing Economic Recovery Package (SHERP), drawn from the Social Housing Investment Fund (SHIF), a $750 million investment to boost the State's social housing by 3,300 properties over the next four years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The first $39 million SHERP New Builds Grant Round 1, announced in early 2022, is currently assisting the community housing sector to deliver more than 170 new social housing dwellings.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Round 2 grant projects will support the community housing sector to deliver new social housing dwellings (houses, units and apartments), transitional housing and crisis accommodation to support vulnerable Western Australians, with a significant investment in regional projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;A number of projects in Round 2 are scheduled to deliver significant social housing benefits to the South-West including Dalyellup, Donnybrook, Busselton and Witchcliffe, while the Shire of Shark Bay will receive an injection of $4 million. This commitment builds upon the State Government's Round 1 investment, where the community housing sector is delivering new social dwellings in the regions including Collie, Brunswick and Dwellingup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Rounds 1 and 2 of the McGowan Government's SHERP Grants Program are set to deliver more than 320 new social housing dwellings across WA. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;The State Government previously announced nearly $58 million in funding through the refurbishment stream of the SHERP Grants Program, which will support 47 community housing providers to undertake more than 800 refurbishment projects of dwellings across WA.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;This is part of the McGowan Government's $2.4 billion investments being made in social housing and homelessness measures, which includes the delivery of 3,300 social houses and the refurbishment and maintenance of many thousands more.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Housing Minister John Carey:&lt;/strong&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; "Our Government's message is clear - we are using every lever at hand, to bolster the supply of social housing across the State.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"We continue to support the Community Housing Sector through two rounds of our SHERP Grants Program, which will help deliver hundreds of new social housing dwellings. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"This significant funding of nearly $40 million is about providing critical financial support to the community housing sector to deliver a wide range of housing initiatives and projects that will support our State's most vulnerable people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"In particular, I'm deeply proud this round of funding continues to deliver a number of projects and new social dwellings across regional WA, including the South-West and to our State's north in Shark Bay.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The funding will provide a further boost to WA's social housing stock and demonstrates the strong partnership between the State Government and the community housing sector.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;"The SHERP Grants Program is a critical part of our Government's $2.4 billion investment in social housing and homelessness measures."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Minister's office - 6552 5300  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;table cellspacing="0" width="100%" class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:20%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Organisation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:20%;"&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;of projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:20%;"&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;of dwellings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:20%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project location/s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:20%;"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Grant funding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advance Housing Limited&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;Dalyellup&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$866,526&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agencies for South-West Accommodation &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;Bunbury&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$5,000,000&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Autism Association &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;Ellenbrook, Spearwood&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$1,979,589&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bethanie Housing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;82&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;Dalyellup, Busselton &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$10,000,000&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bunbury Housing Association&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;Dalyellup, Donnybrook &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$809,155&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Co-operation Housing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;Witchcliffe&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$2,907,486&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Housing Limited&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Caversham, Hamilton Hill, Hilbert, &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;Mount Tarcoola &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$8,984,393&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shire of Perenjori&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;Perenjori&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$878,702&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shire of Shark Bay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;Shark Bay&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$4,118,200&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;St Patricks Community Support Centre &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;Orelia&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$1,648,620&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stellar Living Limited&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;12&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;Byford&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$2,055,378&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UnitingCare West&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;Spearwood &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$313,500&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;19&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;158&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;$39,561,549&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon John Carey BA MLA</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Nearly-$40-million-funding-to-deliver-more-than-150-social-housing-dwellings.aspx</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Lady Ningaloo casts off on the Gascoyne coast</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Lady-Ningaloo-casts-off-on-the-Gascoyne-coast.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A new chapter begins for newly restored vessel Lady Ningaloo, as the Gascoyne's only overnight dive charter service&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;McGowan Government's Regional Economic Development Grants to help local businesses expand and diversify&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regional Development Minister Alannah MacTiernan has today launched Dive Ningaloo's new dive charter vessel at an official naming ceremony in Exmouth.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The newly restored Lady Ningaloo will provide tourists with access to the underwater wonderland of the World Heritage-listed Ningaloo Reef and Muiron Islands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vessel is the only one of its kind in the region, which will be used for high-end liveaboard three or seven-night diving expeditions along the Ningaloo Coast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The vessel refit was partly funded through the Regional Economic Development Grants program - a McGowan Government initiative investing $45.8 million to stimulate economic diversity in the regions.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liveaboard dive charters can be operated year-round and provide an important way of attracting international visitors back to the region. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Regional Development Minister Alannah MacTiernan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"We have supported Dive Ningaloo with the refit of the vessel Lady Ningaloo, providing $200,000 toward the project.  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The new liveaboard dive tours provide a unique experience for visitors to the Ningaloo Coast. It's a great opportunity for the Exmouth region in the lead up to the Ningaloo Total Solar Eclipse in April 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"East coast visitors will have even more reasons to visit the region with new direct Qantas flights to Exmouth from Melbourne commencing from April to October next year." &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister's office - 6552 6200&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Alannah MacTiernan MLC</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Lady-Ningaloo-casts-off-on-the-Gascoyne-coast.aspx</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><title>Gascoyne RED grants backing local business</title><link>https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Gascoyne-RED-grants-backing-local-business.aspx</link><description>&lt;div id="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05__ControlWrapper_RichHtmlField" class="ms-rtestate-field" style="display:inline" aria-labelledby="ctl00_PlaceHolderMain_ctl05_label"&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eight Gascoyne projects share in $609,014 Regional Economic Development Grant funding&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;McGowan Government investing in tourism, hospitality, workforce accommodation and horticulture&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eight Gascoyne projects are set to benefit from funding under round five of the McGowan Government's Regional Economic Development (RED) Grants program. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The McGowan Government's RED Grants program has invested $45.8 million over eight years in local projects across Western Australia's regions, to drive economic development and support regional communities. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Shire of Carnarvon is among the group of successful recipients, receiving $240,000 to build essential workforce accommodation in Carnarvon. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ozsparagus will receive $26,504 to trial production of a white asparagus variety, which attracts a higher market price and net return than other green varieties and can be grown year-round. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Baiyungu Aboriginal Corporation will use $152,000 to construct new tourism infrastructure at Cardabia Station in Coral Bay. The project will support their cultural arts, dance and a music festival coinciding with the 2023 Ningaloo Eclipse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mallard Construction Pty Ltd will use $32,824 to expand operations in Carnarvon. The business is 100% Aboriginal owned and has strong emphasis on employing and training local Aboriginal people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mutts Café in Exmouth will receive $50,000 to expand their café capacity and create a new burger restaurant. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Successful projects in Round five will diversify the tourism and hospitality sector, support new horticultural products, and deliver new workforce accommodation in the region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Regional Development Minister Alannah MacTiernan:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"Round five of the RED grants program will fund a range of projects to increase productivity and business capacity as well as boosting tourism opportunities ahead of the April 2023 Ningaloo Eclipse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The funding will be used to purchase key equipment and infrastructure to deliver new jobs, industry diversification and skills development. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The RED grants continue to support local businesses and organisations to develop, grow and diversify to better service regional communities."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments attributed to Mining and Pastoral Region MLC Peter Foster:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"The McGowan Government has continued to show its ongoing commitment to local businesses and jobs across WA's regions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;"A huge range of projects have been supported this year. I look forward to seeing them deliver benefits to communities across the Gascoyne region."&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Minister's office - 6552 6200&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Successful Round 5 RED Grant recipients - Gascoyne&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;table cellspacing="0" class="ms-rteTable-default" style="text-align:left;width:64%;"&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:33.3333%;"&gt;&lt;strong style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Grant Applicant&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;strong style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Project Description&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:33.3333%;"&gt;&lt;strong style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Grant Amount&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Shire of Carnarvon&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Construction of two multi-worker private bedroom/bathroom houses with shared living facilities on Shire owned land. Providing essential worker accommodation for local businesses. A purpose-specific housing design will be used so that each dwelling could accommodate up to 4 essential workers.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$240,000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Ozsparagus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;To trial production of a white asparagus variety. White asparagus attracts a higher market price and net return than other green varieties and can be grown year-round. Funding to be used to construct new growing domes.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$26,504&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Mallard Construction&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;The project is to expand its operations through construction of a new office and storage facility in the Carnarvon light industrial area. The business is 100% Aboriginal owned and has strong emphasis on employing and training Aboriginal people.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$32,824&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Ningaloo Discovery&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;To refurbish their ageing catamaran for continued commercial use, in time for the 2023 eclipse, to enable scaling up of short sailing tours and private sailing charters.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$65,000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Baiyungu Aboriginal Corporation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;To construct permanent tourism infrastructure at Cardabia Station (Coral Bay); redevelop shearing shed into communal commercial kitchen, water servicing and toilets/ablutions. This will also support the cultural arts, dance and music festival called Jamba Nyinayi Festival at Cardabia Station during the 2023 Ningaloo Eclipse.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$152,000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Mutts Café&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Expand their cafe business into a burger restaurant increasing capacity from 60 to 200 people. Funding will be used for commercial kitchen and equipment for in-house production of ice-cream and plans to be completed prior to the 2023 Ningaloo eclipse.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$50,000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Carnarvon Windfest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;The project will support Windfest 2023 to include three water sports events across the Gascoyne (Shark Bay Downwinder, Carnarvon Windfest, Exmouth Downwinder). The events aim to stimulate the region's economy during the tourism low season. Funding will be used for event management and promotion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$26,000&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Aboriginal Biodiversity Conservation Foundation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default" style="width:53%;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;Purchase a can counting machine to increase the efficiency of the Containers for Change Scheme (C4C) in Carnarvon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;td class="ms-rteTable-default"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:8.8pt;"&gt;$16,686&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/tbody&gt;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><author>Hon Alannah MacTiernan MLC</author><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.mediastatements.wa.gov.au/Pages/McGowan/2022/11/Gascoyne-RED-grants-backing-local-business.aspx</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2022 13:30:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>